good afternoon everybody
welcome to the APRIL 29th 2025
regular meeting of the san
francisco board of supervisors.
MADAM Clerk, will you please
call the roll?
>> thank you, MR. PRESIDENT.
Supervisor chen chen present
supervisor chen chen present
supervisor dorsey dorsey
present supervisor engardio
and engardio present supervisor
fielder fielder present
supervisor mahmood mahmood
present supervisor mandel
present mandel men present
supervisor melgar melgar
present supervisor sadr sadr
present supervisor cheryl
sheryl present and supervisor
walton walton present MR.
PRESIDENT all members are
present.
>> thank you MADAM Clerk the
san francisco board of
supervisors acknowledges that
we are on the unceded ancestral
homeland of the ramakrishna
loney who are the original
inhabitants of the san
francisco peninsula as the
indigenous stewards of this
land in accordance with their
traditions the parameters
colony have never ceded lost
nor forgotten their
responsibilities as the
caretakers of this place as
well as for all peoples who
reside in their traditional
territory as guests we
recognize that we benefit from
living and working on their
traditional homelands.
We wish to pay our respects by
acknowledging the ancestors
elders and relatives of the
ramakrishna only community
and by affirming their
sovereign rights as first
peoples.
Colleagues, I will you join me
in reciting the pledge of
allegiance?
Let me just say one 130 to just
this couple.
>> on behalf of the board I
want to acknowledge the staff
at S.F. Subcommittee and today
particularly haim echevarria
who record each of our meetings
and make the transcripts
available to the public online.
MADAM Clerk, do you have any
communications?
>> yes.
The san francisco board of
supervisors welcomes you all to
attend this meeting in the
boards legislative chamber
within city hall second floor
room 250.
Or if you can't make it down to
the chamber you MAY watch the
proceeding on S.F. Gov't tv's
channel 26 or view the
livestream at ww uw dot S.F.
Geo vtv.Org.
If you would like to submit
public comment and writing you
can send an email to b os at
S.F. Gov dot org or use the
U.S. Postal service.
Just address your envelope to
the san francisco board of
supervisors.
The number one DR. Carlton.
>> be period goodlatte place
city hall room 244 san
francisco, california 94102.
If you need to make a
reasonable accommodation
request under the americans
with disabilities act or to
request request language
assistance please contact the
clerk's office two days
in advance business days
in advance by calling
(415) 554-5184.
Thank you, MR. PRESIDENT.
>> thank you, MADAM Clerk.
Let's go to the approval of our
meeting minutes.
>> yes, we have approval of the
MARCH 25th 2025 board meeting
minutes.
>> all right.
Colleagues, I don't see anyone
in the queue so can I have a
motion to approve the minutes
as presented moved by melgar.
Can I have a second?
Second by walton?
MADAM Clerk, we please call the
roll on the minutes as
presented supervisor dorsey
dorsey eyes supervisor
and engardio and engardio I
supervisor fielder fielder I
supervisor mahmood mahmood I
supervisor randleman.
Hi mandell and I supervisor
melgar I melgar I supervisor
for sadr sadr I supervisor
cheryl cheryl I supervisor
walton walton I supervisor chan
chan I and supervisor chen chen
either are lebanese without
objection the minutes will be
approved after public comment
as presented MAY MADAM Clerk
let's go to our consent agenda
items one through six items one
through six these items are on
consent.
They are considered to be
routine if a member objects an
item MAY be removed
and considered separately.
>> does anyone want to sever
any items from the consent
agenda seeing none MADAM Clerk,
can you please call the roll on
items one through six.
Supervisor dorsey dorsey eyes
supervisor and engardio
engardio I supervisor fielder
fielder I supervisor mahmood
mahmood I supervisor mandolin
hi middleman I supervisor
melgar I melgar I supervisor
sadr sadr I supervisor cheryl
cheryl my supervisor walton
walton I supervisor chan chan I
and supervisor chin chin either
are lebanese without objection
these ordinances are passed on
first reading and finally
passed MADAM Clerk please go to
our regular agenda unfinished
unfinished business item number
seven item seven this is an
ordinance that amends the
planning code to require notice
of rezoning intended to comply
with housing element law and to
affirm the second determination
and to make the appropriate
findings please call the roll
on item seven supervisor dorsey
dorsey no supervisor and gaudio
yes and gaudio I'm supervisor
fielder fielder I'm supervisor
mahmood mahmood no mahmood no.
>> supervisor randleman
middleman I supervisor melgar
no melgar no.
Supervisor sadr.
Sadr I'm supervisor cheryl
cheryl I supervisor walton
walton I supervisor chin chin I
and supervisor chin chin either
are eight eyes and three nose
with supervisor dorsey mahmood
and melgar voting no the
ordinance is finally passed
MADAM Clerk let's go to new
business please call item
number eight item eight this is
an ordinance to appropriate 8.5
million from projected revenue
surplus to appropriate
approximately 3.3 million from
building and structure
improvement and capital renewal
projects at 1235 mission street
and to appropriate 11.8 million
to interdepartmental services
rent paid to real estate and to
the human services agency to
fund one time tenant
improvement and furniture fixes
and equipment costs at 1455
market street pursuant to the
city's new lease for spaces
designated for the human
services agency in fiscal year
2024 through 2025 please call
the roll on item eight
supervisor dorsey dorsey eyes
supervisor and engardio
and guardian eyes supervisor
fielder fielder I supervisor
mahmood mahmood eyes supervisor
mandolin hi management I
supervisor melgar I melgar eyes
supervisor sutter sutter eyes
supervisor cheryl cheryl I
supervisor walton walton eyes
supervisor chan chan I
and supervisor chin chin either
R.A. Lebanese or without
objection this ordinance is
passed on first reading MADAM
Clerk can you please call item
nine?
>> item nine is a resolution to
approve and authorize the
director of property on behalf
of the human services agency
the county transportation
authority and the libraries
information technology unit to
execute a first amendment to
the lease agreement with hudson
1455 market llc to take an
additional approximately
226,000 of rentable square feet
of office space
and approximately 6000 rentable
square feet of basement storage
at 1455 market street for the
balance of an initial term of
21 years to expend an amount of
approximately 897,000 for rent,
parking and electrical costs
in fiscal year 2024 25 with a
base rent of approximately 1.9
million for the initial year
plus approximately 42,000 of
basement storage for fiscal
year 20 2526 with two five year
options to extend and rent of
approximately $4,141.20 per
square foot with 3% annual
increases thereafter and to
authorize the director of real
estate to the extent of
available operating budget
and to the extent not covered
by the tenant improvement
allowance to expend an amount
not to exceed 15.5 million for
digital technology costs tenant
improvements, alternatives
and furniture fixtures
and equipment and to authorize
the director of property to
execute amendments.
Let's take this item same
house, same call without
objection the resolution is
adopted.
MADAME Clerk please call item
ten.
>> item ten this is a
resolution to retroactively
approve and authorize the
director of property and behalf
of the department of
homelessness and support of
housing to execute a lease of
real property with roshan
investments llc for use of the
a dante hotel located at 610
geary street for a non
congregate temporary shelter
program with 93 units for an
initial term of one year to
commence APRIL 1st 2025 with
one one year option to extend
and an annual base rent of 1.5
million with 3% annual
increases if the city exercises
the option to extend and a
maximum final payment of up to
100,000 upon surrender of the
property and to affirm the
second determination and to
make the appropriate findings
let's take this item same
house, same call without
objection this resolution is
adopted.
MADAM Clerk, please call item
11.
>> item 11 this is a resolution
to adopt the city's five year
information and community
technology plan for fiscal year
2025 through 2026 through 2029
through 2030.
Pursuant to the administrative
code section 22 8.6 and we can
take this same house same call
without objection this
resolution is adopted.
>> MADAM Clerk, please call
item 12 item 12 this is a
resolution to retroactively
authorize the planning
department to accept and expend
a $7 million grant award
JANUARY 22nd 2025 through
SEPTEMBER 30th 2030 from the
united states department of
housing and urban development
pathways to removing obstacles
to housing grant program and we
can take this item same house,
same call without objection the
resolution is adopted.
MADAM Clerk, can you please
call items 13 and 14 together?
>> items 13 and 14 together.
Item 13 is a resolution to
designate the newspapers to be
the outreach community based
weekly newspaper for outreach
advertising for fiscal year
2025 through 2026 the bay area
reporter serving the lesbian,
gay, bisexual and transgender
community elder botero for
their bayview bernal heights
and mission neighborhoods it'll
take a lot day for the mission
neighborhood the henry society
journal for the bayview hunters
point and visitation valley
neighborhoods the no valley
voice for the noah valley
neighborhoods.
Potrero view serving the
dogpatch eastern south of
market mission bay and potrero
hill neighborhoods the san
francisco bay times for the
castro to boast triangle
and the no valley neighborhoods
sing dow daily for the
chinatown excelsior ingleside
merced heights ocean view outer
mission portola valley richmond
sunset and tenderloin
neighborhoods small business
exchange serving the entire
city the win newspaper for the
chinatown excelsior outer
mission north beach the
portillo richmond sunset
tenderloin and visitation
valley neighborhoods the world
journalists serving the bayview
hunters point chinatown mission
south of market tenderloin
visitation valley and the
western addition neighborhoods
for fiscal year 2025 through
2026 and for item 14 this
resolution designate is the san
francisco examiner to be the
official newspaper of the city
and county of san francisco for
all official advertising for
fiscal year 2025 through 2026
and we can take these items
same house, same call without
objection these resolutions are
adopted.
MADAM Clerk, please call item
15.
>> item 15 this is a resolution
to authorize the office of
contract administration to
execute a contract between the
city and ser costa iron
and metal co company inc for
the as needed sale of city
owned scrap metal for pick up
and disposal for a five year
term JUNE 1st 2025 through MAY
31st 2030 for an estimated
revenue amount of approximately
1 million and we can take this
same house same call without
objection the resolutions
adopted MADAM Clerk, please
call item 16 and 17 together.
Item 16 and 17 are two
resolutions authorizing
contract amendments for the
city administra da's office
through the director of risk
management division.
Item 16 authorizes a contract
for insurance brokerage
services with arthur j.
Gallagher and company risk
management services llc for an
amount not to exceed 30 million
for a three year term through
JUNE 30th 2028 with an option
to renew for six additional
years and item 17 authorizes a
contract for insurance
and brokerage services with
alliant insurance services inc
for 85 million for a three year
term to commence JULY 1st 2025
through JUNE 30th 2028 for both
items and we'll take these
items same house, same call
without objection these
resolutions are adopted.
>> MADAM Clerk, can you please
call item 18?
Item 18 resolution to authorize
the airport commission to
accept and expend an
approximate $66.2 million grant
and any additional amounts up
to 15% of the original grant
that MAY be offered from the
federal aviation administration
for the implementation of the
boarding area g gates
enhancement project OCTOBER
1st, 2024 through SEPTEMBER
30th 2028 contingent on receipt
by the airport commission of an
airport infrastructure grant
offer from the federal aviation
administration and we can take
this same house same call
without objection the
resolution is adopted.
MADAME Clerk, can you please
call item 19?
>> item 19 this is a resolution
to retroactively authorize the
fleet management division to
accept and expend an in-kind
gift of a zero emission
passenger vehicle a rivian r
and r1s from daniel lurie
retrofitted with appropriate
security upgrades with an
estimated market value of
approximately 134,000 for use
of the official city business.
Effective MARCH 18th 2025.
>> same house, same call
without objection the
resolutions adopted.
MADAM Clerk, can you please
call item 20?
>> item 20 this is a resolution
to approve and authorize the
general manager of the san
francisco public utilities
commission to execute a
contract as if puc customer
administrative services
community choice aggregation
program with calpine community
energy a division of calpine
energy solutions llc for 17
million a duration of three
years to commence APRIL 30th
2025 through APRIL 30th 2028 to
provide meter data management
billing and customer care
services.
>> let's take this item same
house, same call.
>> without objection the
resolutions adopted.
And MADAM Clerk, can you please
call items 21 through 24
together items 21 through 24
are for resolutions that
approve and accept and expend
grants from the U.S. Department
of housing and urban urban
development.
Item 21 approves the fiscal
year 2025 through 2026
emergency solutions grant
program and authorizes the
mayor on behalf of the city to
apply for, accept and expend
the 2025 through 26 esg program
entitlement from the united
states department of housing
and urban development for
approximately 1.9 million
starting JULY 1st, 2025.
>> item 22 approves the
community development block
grant program in the amount of
up to approximately 20.1
million and to expend estimated
program income in the amount of
5.8 million for a combined
total of approximately 26
million through the date when
the funds are all expended.
Item 23 approves the fiscal
year 20 2526 housing
opportunities for persons with
aids program in the amount of 8
million and to expand program
income and reprogramed funds of
20 of two excuse me 202,000 for
a combined total of 8.2 million
through JUNE 30th 2028.
And item 24 this resolution
approves the home investment
partnership home program in the
amount of approximately 5.3
million and expands program
income for 2 million for a
combined total of approximately
7.3 million through JUNE 30th
2030 and we can take these
items same house, same call
without objection these
resolutions are adopted.
>> MADAM Clerk, please call
item 25.
Item 25 is an ordinance to
amend the planning code to
eliminate the 200 foot buffer
restriction in the western soma
special use district for
nighttime entertainment and to
affirm the sacred determination
and to make the appropriate
findings.
>> and we could take this same
house same call without
objection this ordinance is
passed on first reading MADAM
Clerk please call item 26 item
26 this is an ordinance to
amend the existing building
code to assess the city's
inventory of seismically
vulnerable rigid wall flexible
diaphragm and concrete
buildings and to adopt
voluntary seismic retrofit
standards for such buildings.
To adopt findings of local
conditions under the california
health and safety code to
affirm the secret determining
motion and to make the
appropriate findings.
>> same house, same call
without it without objection
this ordinance is passed on
first reading MADAM Clerk,
please call item 27 item 27
this is a resolution to adopt
the sunset chinese cultural
district's cultural history
housing and economic
sustainability strategy report
under administrative code
section 107.5.
>> let's take this same house
same call.
>> without objection the
resolutions adopted.
>> MADAM Clerk, please call
item number 28 item 28 this is
a resolution to declare the
city's real property located at
772 pacific as exempt surplus
land and to make the
appropriate findings we can
take this same house same call.
Without objection the
resolutions adopted.
MADAM Clerk, can you please
call item 29 item 29 this is an
ordinance to amend the
administrative code to create
the valencia street
entertainment zone.
The street entertainment zone
and the yerba buena lane
downtown activation location to
affirm the secret determination
and to make the appropriate
findings.
>> we'll take this same house
same call without objection the
ordinance is passed on first
reading MADAME Clerk please
call item 30.
>> item 30.
This is a resolution to accept
the annual surveillance reports
under administrative code
section 19 b point six for the
airport.
The arts commission, the asian
art museum, child support
services, the city
administrator's office.
The department of elections.
The department of emergency
management.
Department of homelessness
and support of housing.
Department of human resource is
the department of public
health.
The department of public works.
The department of technology.
The fire department.
The human services agency.
Juvenile probation department.
The municipal transportation
agency.
The police department.
The port of san francisco.
The public library.
The public utilities
commission.
Recreation and parks
department.
The rent stabilization
and arbitration board and the
war memorial department.
>> let's take this same house,
same call without objection,
this resolution is adopted.
>> MADAM Clerk, can you please
call item 31?
>> item 31 this is a motion to
appoint michael reed.
Irina neu.
Terms ending APRIL 30th, 2026
and mikayla garfinkle nicholas
chapman, dana sherwood
and michael angelo torres terms
ending APRIL 30th 2027 to the
commission of animal control
and welfare.
>> same house, same call
without objection this motion
is approved.
>> MADAM Clerk, can you please
call item 32 and I will hand
the gavel over to supervisor
one.
Item 32 this is a motion to
reappoint supervisor rafael
mandolin to the association of
bay area governments executive
board term ending JUNE 30th,
2027 or to the conclusion of
his term as member of the board
of supervisors.
>> thank you MADAM Clerk and I
like to make a motion to excuse
PRESIDENT Amendment from item
32 I see a motion made by below
and second and are moved
and seconded by supervisor chin
.
>> we take a roll call and it
on item 30 two.
>> supervisor dorsey dorsey
eyes supervisor and gaudio
in gaudio I supervisor fielder
fielder I supervisor mahmood
mahmood I supervisor melgar I
melgar I supervisor sadr sadr I
supervisor cheryl cheryl I
supervisor walton walton I
supervisor chan chan I
and supervisor chen chin either
are too nice thank you motion
to excuse PRESIDENT Amendment
from adam 32 carries and I
believe we can we still haven't
voted on item yet and I believe
we can take the item.
>> same house same call MADAM
Clerk or item ten MR. PRESIDENT
3232 that's correct.
>> well, we took the roll call
vote so we took the roll call
to excuse me, gentlemen.
>> my apologies, MR. PRESIDENT.
I thought you indicated mahmood
.
>> yes, you're correct.
We'll take that same house,
same car, same house, same call
.
>> I'm 32.
Approve.
>> thank you.
Supervisor all thank you,
colleagues my MADAM Clerk came
33 call out.
>> yep.
That would be 33.
Item 33 this is a motion to
reappoint supervisor matt
dorsey as a member to the
association of bay area
governments executive board
term ending JUNE 30th 2027 or
to the conclusion of his term
as member of the board of
supervisors.
All right.
Can I have a motion to excuse
supervisor dorsey moved by
sorter seconded by cheryl and i
think without objection.
Supervisor dorsey is excused
then MADAM.
>> well thought out and then
MADAM Clerk, can you please
call the roll on item 33
supervisor engardio
and engardio I supervisor
fielder fielder I supervisor
mahmood mahmood I supervisor
mendelson I mendelson I
supervisor melgar I melgar I
supervisor sadr sadr I
supervisor cheryl cheryl I
supervisor walton walton I
supervisor chen chan I
and supervisor chin chin I
there are ten eyes all right
without objection the motion is
approved.
>> and MADAM Clerk let's go to
committee reports.
>> yes, committee reports we
have item 42 was considered by
the land use and transportation
committee at a regular meeting
on monday APRIL 28th and was
recommended as a committee
report with the same title.
Item 42 is a resolution to
approve an amendment of the
mission rock housing plan to
reduce the minimum percentage
of inclusionary affordable
housing units per phase of the
mission rocks project at c will
lot 337 bounded by china basin
channel third street, mission
rock street and the san
francisco bay please call the
roll on item 42 supervisor
dorsey dorsey eyes supervisor
and gaudio and gaudio I
supervisor fielder fielder I
supervisor mahmood mahmood I
supervisor mandolin hi melman I
supervisor melgar I melgar I
supervisor sartor sutter I
supervisor cheryl cheryl I
supervisor walton walton i
supervisor chin chin I
and supervisor chen chin I
there are 11 eyes without
objection this resolution is
adopted MADAM Clerk it is
almost 230 there we go.
>> can you call or 230 special
order or 230 special order is
the recognition the recognition
of commendations for
meritorious service to the city
and county of san francisco
and we will start today with
district seven supervisor
melgar.
>> oh, thank you, PRESIDENT
Mandell if I could ask mark
selby and angelica medina selby
to come up please.
All right.
Thank you PRESIDENT Mandel men
today I am honoring two of my
constituents mark selby
and angelica medina selby who
have been generously dedicating
their time to keeping district
seven public spaces immaculate
and beautiful for more than 50
years.
Mark and angelica have been
cleaning up litter on our
streets in our parks
particularly in their
neighborhood forest knolls
and around the reservoir and on
the reservoir trash picker
and bag in hand mark
and angelica have routinely
cleaned the frequent
amalgamation of detritus
in golden gate park, clarendon
heights and the parking lot
behind the legion of honor as
their own form of civic
engagement.
However, mark and angelica
civic engagement does not just
stop at maintaining the
cleanliness and beauty of
district seven.
mark has deep roots in san
francisco.
His maternal grandfather lived
through the 1906 earthquake
and camped in dolores park for
a few days after the
earthquake.
His father was once also
recognized for his neighborhood
work.
Mark is a product of san
francisco public schools
and are dispatched ph.D. At
ucsf also in district seven, he
met angelica who immigrated
from chile and was a visiting
scholar at ucsf.
They raised two sons who also
attended san francisco public
schools prior to their
retirement.
Mark and angelica played a
significant role both
in biotechnology and the
pharmaceutical industries as a
scientist at novartis vaccines
angelica played an instrumental
role in the development of the
happy vaccine.
>> thank you angelica and mark
played a critical role in the
development of the first anti
pd one antibody drug test that
initiate drug that initiated a
major transformation in cancer
treatment and immuno oncology.
Their commitment to community
and to making this a better
world into service is admirable
and has grown more impactful
each year as they start
cleaning more areas making them
beautiful.
>> they also volunteer to
supply the local reservoir with
at doorways, bags keeping our
public spaces clean and yet
another way.
Thank you mark and angelica for
keeping our public spaces clean
for inspiring other residents
to be better stewards of the
environment for your long time
and community dedication
and work you represent the best
of san francisco.
>> I also want to acknowledge
your awesome neighbors who are
in the audience.
If you could please stand up
I'd appreciate it especially
lily walter kaplan from tourist
no and nancy from midtown
terrace who put your name
forward.
It also always seeing your
praises.
>> so thank you so much.
Well, thank you very much for
that acknowledgment and it's
much appreciated you took some
of the wind out of my sails
because I was going to say a
few other things in particular
acknowledging walter who was
our local community activist
who was highly engaged in the
community and is a wonderful
guy now speaking for my wife
and myself we typically don't
want to draw attention to the
work we do to keep san
francisco clean.
>> we just do it on our own but
is an honor that is bestowed on
us if we can provoke others to
do the same then it's it's a
worthwhile endeavor.
Now as you heard, my family has
a long history in san francisco
dating back to before the 1906
earthquake.
As such I consider myself a san
francisco boy although now an
aging senior but I still have
enough energy to do some more
cleaning and there's still dirt
and garbage to be picked up now
my wife and calico is an
immigrant from chile who after
arriving immediately
appreciated the natural beauty
of san francisco.
We've been married for some 43
years after meeting at ucsf
where we're both studying.
We've had decades long careers
in biotech and are more or less
retired.
As an aside, we urge you all to
stand up for science in the
face of attacks on our
institution of higher learning.
As a second largest employer
in san francisco which has
seated numerous pioneering
biotech companies ucsf requires
and merits our support.
Now back to cleaning.
We are not limited to clarendon
neighborhood where we live but
as you heard we cleaned
in golden gate park since
retirement that is about 3 or 4
times a week.
As always a fair amount of
garbage to pick up
and occasionally in sigma turn
grove and monthly and a palace
of lena legion of honor.
>> now why do we do this?
>> because we hate to see one
of the most beautiful cities
in the world tarnished by
unsightly trash.
We are fortunate to live in a
municipality where parks are
many give us a respite from the
if you will.
Bland, concrete, dull asphalt
and rows of stucco structures
that abound.
Nature's beauty gives us peace
of mind, promotes being one
with nature and provides an
escape from urban life.
And indeed, you know, these
chaotic times it's a very
welcome respite.
Now if you see me on the street
or my wife with me and we're
in the park with a trash bag
in one hand and a picker in the
other, please don't mistake us
for vagrants.
It has been done before so
little odd.
It's rather remarkable that
when we are passing folks while
picking up trash most ignore us
or look away.
Only a few will venture words
of appreciation.
But again we don't seek
appreciation for what we're
doing.
We'd also like to acknowledge
interestingly enough the 311
act app and the developers
thereof.
In those cases where there are
no trash bins in proximity we
can pull the bags of garbage,
take a photo and submit to 311.
The city picks up the trash
in a timely manner.
Alternatively one can deposit
trash in cans conveniently
situated in goal and gay park
and near fire stations as it
were.
Thus there is really no excuse
for not picking up especially
if you have the time.
Now I don't know how to
encourage others to do what we
do except by example.
>> I know there are organized
efforts which is wonderful but
for those who appreciate
flexibility and issue
structured groups it would be
great to encourage individual
contributors.
I'll leave it up to others to
find ways to encourage san
franciscans to be good
shepherds of our green spaces.
In closing, we are among the
ranks of antitrust citizens who
take this task upon ourselves
exemplify it by the author
david sedaris.
If you listen to npr as we do,
you probably will know that
david sedaris trash story as
good urban warrior as we
soldier had equipped with a
trash bag and a picker driven
by the goal of a landscape
devoid of man's detritus.
Let us keep san francisco clean
so visitors and residents alike
can revel in its natural beauty
and well-maintained parks.
>> as I always said, we can
walk and chew gum at the same
time and pick up trash.
Okay
?
>> all right.
Now we will go to district nine
supervisor fielder.
>> thank you.
I would like to welcome the man
to the podium.
Please come up la mayor.
Today I am honoring a truly
remarkable woman a pillar of
strength, compassion
and resilience.
La moya la mayor.
Abuela is the heart and soul
behind the most cafe in the
mission district.
>> temos cafe is more than just
a coffee shop.
It's a refuge.
>> a place where?
A place where the worries of
the outside world fall away.
>> it's a space built on
community connection and love.
>> rooted deeply in the mayor's
palestinian heritage and woven
into the vibrant spirit of the
mission.
>> from the beginning la man
made it her mission to serve
not just coffee but humanity.
she offers warmth
and generosity to everyone who
walks through the doors.
>> whether it's a meal for
someone in need or a seat at
the table to celebrate life's
important milestones her
journey has not been easy.
Coming to san francisco as a
young woman from palestine, she
faced cultural barriers,
economic hardships and personal
loss.
>> there were times when middle
eastern food was unfamiliar to
the community and times when
grief could have easily
overwhelmed her.
>> but la mer met every
challenge with strength,
resilience and an unwavering
commitment to move forward.
Each day she rises before dawn
works long hours and continues
to care for her family here
and back home in palestine.
>> even with so much on her
shoulders she still makes time
for herself.
Showing a quiet strength that
inspires everyone around her
including myself.
>> la mer has created more than
a business she has created a
home.
Temos cafe is a bridge between
cultures palestinian
and latino.
Two communities that share
values of resilience, warmth
and deep respect for family
and tradition.
She reminds us that leadership
isn't about competition or
titles.
>> it's about standing strong
and who you are leading with
heart and building with love.
>> today we honor la mia for
the sanctuary she has created
the countless lives she has
touched and the example she
sets for all of us in the
community.
She shows us that real
community is built one
connection at a time.
Through small acts of kindness,
through patience and through
perseverance.
>> on behalf of everyone who
has been fortunate to walk
through temos cafe thank you la
mia.
Your generous city, your
strength and your beautiful
spirit inspires us all.
Thank you and GOD thank you for
your thanks.
Exactly.
You make me cry.
>> good afternoon.
My name is lamia abas.
The proud owner of themas cafe
a palestinian family owned.
>> we have been part of this
community for 11 years and in
that time we have learned that
running a small business is
about more than just coffee.
>> it's about connection
bringing people together.
Our goal at teams has always
been to make every person feel
welcome and feel home.
A team owns each cup of coffee
has been a chance to build
relationship share stories
and contribute with the heart
of the cesar chavez community.
Running a small business has
it's a challenge but it's also
deeply rewarding.
>> I hope to continue growing
learning and serving our
neighborhood for many more
years to come.
And thank you jackie for all
the beautiful mice you see.
>> I appreciate it.
thank you.
And next up we have district
four supervisor and engardio
colleagues.
>> today I'd like to honor the
late lieutenant colonel robert
powell.
He was the senior army
instructor for the jrotc
program at abraham lincoln high
school for 28 years.
During his tenure, lincoln's
jrotc program was rated as one
of the most successful ones
in western united states by the
department of the army.
It was so well run that colonel
powell also became the director
of army instruction for all the
jrotc programs in the san
francisco school district.
He taught his cadets many
leadership skills that prepared
them for life skills such as
how to deal with conflicts with
poise and grace and how to
communicate succinctly
and efficiently.
He was a respected mentor not
just to his own cadets but to
students in the broader
community.
He did so by opening up the
jrotc facilities to students to
gather during lunch and after
school and counseling teenagers
who were going through
challenges.
Our own budget and finance
clerk brant haley has served
under colonel powell as a
battalion commander at lincoln
high school in 1994.
He credits colonel powell for
providing guidance and molding
him into the effective public
servant he is today.
Before joining lincoln high
school's jrotc program, colonel
powell had a 23 year decorated
career in the military, began
at fort benning, georgia.
Ri attended airborne jump
school.
He was later assigned a
checkpoint charlie in germany,
which was best known as a
crossing between east and west
berlin.
He also served and was injured
in vietnam where he received a
purple heart.
His other awards include a
bronze star with valor
and commendation award with
valor for heroism and combat at
a merit merit service medal.
He retired from his military
career here in san francisco at
the presidio in 1982 and that's
when he turned to servicing the
youth at lincoln.
Lieutenant colonel powell
passed away peacefully APRIL
13th at the age of 88.
He is survived by his wife
emily daughters robin
and rhonda powell and the
thousands of cadets at lincoln
high school who he inspired to
be their best selves.
And colleagues are going to
continue today at lincoln high
school.
I have the privilege of
honoring some of the brightest
and most hardworking young
people from the sun sets.
The outstanding students of
abraham lincoln high school
because they have had an
exception all year both
in academics and athletics.
Let's start with academics.
I would like the lincoln mock
trial team to stand please.
But for the lincoln mock trial
team won their first ever
citywide championship.
The lincoln defense team
appeared in the federal
courthouse before a united
states district court judge
and defeated last year's winner
st ignatius and after this
historic victory they went on
to compete at the state level
and one of the students won
best witness award.
So this is the result of hard
work the students practice
three hours after school every
week plus practices on weekends
and hosting zoom office hours.
Coach amanda our south us oh
sorry our south ski and jesse
lanier are full time lawyers
who have full time lawyers who
volunteer their time to mentor
the students.
Congratulations to the team.
They have impressed their peers
with their deep legal insights,
school spirit and wonderful
teamwork.
>> they have made their school
proud and I like to invite
coach jesse lanier coach jesse
lanier to come speak on behalf
of the mock trial team.
>> thank you.
Coach lanier my name is jesse
lanier and I'm one of the
coaches of lincoln's
championship mock trial team.
My co coach amanda wysocki
quite all right.
Could not be here with us today
because a little baby maker her
first is due any day.
>> we are so thankful to you
supervisor for recognizing us
and to the city for recognizing
the accomplishments of these
students today.
>> with us here are some truly
extraordinary young people.
So often the attorneys get most
of the praise at a mock trial
competition.
i'm an attorney.
I get it.
But at lincoln our attorneys
are witnesses and our courtroom
staff are all stars.
They're winning record speaks
for itself.
These students are smart,
hardworking and so talented.
>> but they're also funny
and silly and kind.
What a gift you are to your
school, to the city, to your
families and to me as a coach I
think often about how our
students benefit from
undertaking this exercise.
>> what do we learn
collectively from our
regardless of our roles from
mock trial?
>> it isn't just that we learn
to act like an attorney, to act
like a bailiff or a clerk or a
timekeeper to act like a
defendant on trial for his life
.
>> we learn how to use facts to
tell a story.
>> we learn the value of
sticking to those facts rather
than bending them until they
break.
>> we learn to be curious about
what we do not know to listen
to watch.
>> we learn to persuade.
To advocate.
We learn how to develop the
facets of our authentic selves
that best serve the tasks at
hand.
>> we learn how to work around
decisions that we think are
incorrect or unfair.
>> and we learn empathy with
the characters we play and the
positions that they're in.
We also learn professionalism
and precision.
>> we learn that good
sportsmanship is a value not
limited to losing.
>> and we learn that words are
powerful and that the way that
we use them matters.
>> I think we all can agree
that these are not just lessons
that make us all well-rounded
individuals.
>> the values derived from
these lessons are fundamental
to a functioning democracy.
>> and these values are
in short supply.
>> but not for long.
Not for long because these
students are on the way.
And in fact they were asking me
procedural questions during the
proceedings earlier.
>> so I think we're we're
in good shape.
>> another lesson we learn
in mock trial is that a captive
audience loses interest in a
speaker very quickly.
>> so I'm going to close now
with this.
Win or lose, I am so proud to
be your coach.
I am so excited about what's
next for you.
For the departing seniors don't
forget us when you're famous
please.
And for the 2025 2026 rising
sophomores, juniors and seniors
rest up, folks.
Study those objections because
the case packets for next year
come out in just five months.
>> and then it'll be time once
again to lock in.
Thank you so much.
All right.
We're not done.
We have more we're going to
talk about lincoln's excellence
in athletics.
>> now I would like the boys
varsity basketball team to
stand boys varsity basketball
team stand up.
>> all right.
Okay.
So so get this.
They just won their fourth
consecutive san francisco
section championship four in a
row.
And then they went on to the
state semifinal finals.
Lincoln was the number 15 seed
team and they nearly beat the
number three seed team.
They fell short just by three
points.
An incredible achievement.
And I also want to give a
special shout out to the team
captain lutz.
He played in all four
championship seasons from
freshman to senior year which
is a rare achievement at the
high school level.
And so beyond behind this
success it's not just the
players but an incredible
support team including student
managers, coaches and advisors
that help the team stay
prepared and focus.
So congratulations to the whole
team.
Go mustangs.
>> all right.
And I want to invite coach karl
jacobs to come up and say a few
words.
>> coach jacobs, thank you.
And when we're done with the
remarks, we'll ask the mock
trial team and the basketball
team to exit the chambers
and go up to the rotunda
and we'll take some group
photos.
Good afternoon, everyone.
to the board of supervisors
supervising audio.
I want to thank you.
Thank you first of all for
recognizing colonel powell from
lincoln high school.
MAY he rest in peace.
Great man.
Thank you for showing our young
people that you care for them
still is very important because
both teams these are
extracurricular activities that
they participate in which means
they stay after school when a
lot of students are going home,
they'll steal their putting
in hours of work and they
deserve to be commended for
that.
They make big sacrifices.
You know, it's not just even
with sports.
It's not just fun and games.
These young men put in a lot of
hard work and I'm very thankful
for that and very proud of them
for that.
We ask a lot of them.
And on top of everything else
they're supposed to do at home
and at school.
All right.
So they do deserve a thank you
for this and I think they
starting to get it used to
coming here.
That's winning four in a row.
I think this is their
motivation.
So now my start using this at
the beginning of the season hey
you guys want to go to city
hall?
Let's see what a supervisor.
Let's go.
And I think this is a
motivating factor.
I'm thankful for our principal
not I'd community who stands
behind us.
You know it's hard at a public
school.
It's hard in a public school.
But we don't consider ourself
like that.
We compete at the highest
level.
And these young men they come
out and all our students
probably the debate team as
well or they all come out
and they put in the hard work
and they put in the time.
And we don't think of ourselves
as just a public school.
We think of ourselves.
I just competitors I'm proud to
represent our city.
And that's what I'm thankful
for these guys they proud to
represent the city of san
francisco.
And thank you again for
recognizing us
.
>> all right.
District five supervisor
mahmood thank you, PRESIDENT
Colleagues today in recognition
again of the end of
arab-american heritage month.
I'm excited to be honoring
ghazi shami, the founder
and ceo of empire because you
want to come up here with your
family.
>> all your family can join as
well.
Yeah, my family's not here but
my extended family is extended
families which is my coworkers
who I'm so very proud of.
So if they want to come up you
guys can come up with me.
>> come on up.
Ghazi is the founder and ceo of
empire, the largest privately
held independent record label
distributor and publisher
in the united states.
It's founded in 2010 right here
in san francisco.
Ghazi built empire into a
global force an empire one
could even say ushering in a
new era of thriving independent
artists and reasserting san
francisco as a center for
culture and the arts.
I first met ghazi earlier this
year when we were coordinating
on collaborating on a
tenderloin eat street fair.
I felt the security to get
in the building was harder than
the mayor's.
But getting inside I felt it
was like a family.
They had created with all of
your coworkers we talked about
your family, your children,
your wife who's given me a lot
of wedding advice since then
but also your employees and I
care.
I saw how much you cared about
bringing people from all over
the world from palestine even
to the bay area to give them a
better life.
Give them the opportunities
that I know san francisco gave
you as well.
>> and I saw in that day ghazi
and I shared a vision where
arabs and muslims could
leverage san francisco as the
birthplace for their dreams of
upward mobility.
And he was not only open to
partnering as an organizer of
the event but he brought a
young palestinian artist to
perform for the community.
That honestly that was what
they were most excited for.
That day we held the street
fair.
Ghazi himself was born
and raised in the city and used
to live and work in the
tenderloin which I represent as
well.
And his exact role model I know
these kids in the tenderloin
over 30,000 of them deserve
and see every day.
He's the son of a palestinian
war refugee with humble
beginnings and a relentless
spirit that led him to take
night classes at S.F. State
university for audio and video
engineering while working
in burlingame assembling
computers.
>> since then he followed his
passion to develop early stage
artists and worked with award
winning artists like kendrick
lamar and anderson park.
>> share your distracts are
pretty good too.
>> this year is a significant
year as empire celebrates 15
years of success.
Ghazi was recently featured on
the cover of billboard magazine
which we have a copy of him
here signed by all the board of
supervisors as well.
>> over the years he's been
recognized by various leading
music and culture publications
for his contributions to the
music industry including
billboard power players, indie
power players and r&b hip hop
power players.
He made the rolling stone
feature 25 list the variety
deal maker impact report
and was named by variety
magazine as a top 50 hip-hop
executive of all time.
>> ghazi has been featured
in press such as new york times
,forbes music business
worldwide, san francisco
chronicle and more and served
as keynote speaker at south by
southwest human acts
and bitcoin.Com france.
Gazi provides a unique
perspective with his grasp of
the creative business
and technological aspects of
the modern music industry.
His strong business acumen has
scaled empire to a global
operation in five continents
and 20 countries.
And despite that, gazi has
never forgotten his roots
in san francisco.
>> he recently purchased one
montgomery, an iconic san
francisco landmark building as
empires new global headquarters
and he continues to be an
advocate for human rights
and invests in cultural events
for our arab and muslim
community locally to build
connections and uplift our
city's diversity.
Gazi is the embodiment of san
francisco's values.
>> he is humble a humanitarian
community builder, champion of
the arts and he's committed to
invigorating the very soul of
our city.
>> so colleagues, please join
me in commending gazi shami on
his immense impact on san
francisco and culture worldwide
for his relentless hope in our
city and for never forgetting
where he came from.
>> I hope we can all see
and hear more from his work
in the years to come.
But before but but first but
first supervisor walton thank
you PRESIDENT Middlemen.
My apologies.
Supervisor mahmud but I just
wanted to chime in and wanted
just to say thank you to ghazi
for all of the opportunities
that you provide for young
people particularly the young
people here in san francisco
and across california.
>> and I also want to just
thank you for the way you
represent your culture and your
community.
It's important that everyone
gets the opportunity to see
that in the way you carry
yourself as a family man and a
true leader like supervisor
mahmud said, you are a very
humble person.
What a lot of accolades and so
I'm just proud to have you as a
son of san francisco and proud
that this is happening here at
the board of supervisors
and the last thing I would just
say is thank you for keeping
your business in san francisco
because we have no record
companies particularly to the
to the magnitude and size of
empire that are based here
and stay at home.
So thank you so much for
everything that you do.
>> thank you.
>> good afternoon, everybody.
That was a little overwhelming
.
So I'm going to take a second
to gather my thoughts and I
didn't prepare a speech.
I prefer to speak from the
heart but I'm a firm believer
in community and I'm also a
firm believer in paying it
forward and being the change
you want to see.
And san francisco's the
birthplace of my family.
And what I mean by that is my
uncle came to potrero hill
in the 50s through ellis island
and my whole entire family came
through material hill.
I was born in poor hill.
My first studio an office was
in potrero hill.
So I'm a firm believer
in always bringing everything
back to its root.
And san francisco's at the root
of who I am as a human.
>> and so I think it would have
been a great disservice for me
to build this company anywhere
else than in a place that gave
me the tools, the direction
and certainly the inspiration
and to build the company that
I've built.
I'm definitely a product of my
environment and I think doing
this anywhere else wouldn't
have felt so special.
>> so you guys mentioned one
montgomery when we were a kid
my mom would bank at
in westlake at crocker bank.
And so we owned a coin operated
laundromat and from the time I
was four years old my dad would
let me stuffed the coins in the
little pouches and wrap up
hundred dollar bills and go
make the deposit at the
merchant window.
I got about halfway through the
deal of purchasing one
montgomery and I realized that
it used to be crocker bank
because I saw a clock on the
floor.
And I used to sleep with a
little dog, a stuffed animal
and it was called a cocker
spaniel.
And they gave it to me at
crocker bank when I was a
little kid.
And it was a very surreal
moment because embodies the
spirit of 360 moments where
everything that you work for
in life makes sense.
And I think nothing
crystallizes that reality more
than being here in the city of
san francisco.
So I'm very honored to stand
before the board of supervisors
until now coming into
government buildings used to
give me uneasy feelings because
I probably had to pay a fine
in a different chapter of my
life.
Now it's giving me an uneasy
feeling because I'm nervous to
stand before you.
But I'm very proud of my staff
of the people I get to call my
family.
Without them none of this is
possible without my courageous
wife who used to sleep on the
floor with me in the studio.
It's been a long climb.
And we got so much further to
go.
And I promise to always
represent the city with a
certain level of integrity
and excellence because that's
all you could do at the end of
the day is just be excellent.
So thank you so much
.
>> all right.
And last but not least from
district eight saeed and hisham
basu.
>> come on up.
>> maybe not yet quite as
famous in the world but
certainly famous and beloved
in district eight.
>> yes.
>> so also in commemoration of
national arab-american heritage
month it is my great honor to
present a special commendation
to sidney shaw embassy so say
in his own buffalo whole foods
and know hill market to
businesses in district eight
castro neighborhood noho market
has been owned and operated by
the family for 26 years
and buffalo whole foods has
been operated by the family I
believe for 25 of its 50 years
before the family purchased it
in 2021 when saeed and his
mom's father sammy died of
covid related complications
in 2021 there was an outpouring
of grief and support from the
castro community and beyond.
Sammy was simply beloved by the
neighborhood.
The brothers learned to run
their stores with the spirit of
kindness that their father
embodied.
>> they were both born at
kaiser hospital on geary.
They grew up in the sunset
and went to westmore high
school in daly city.
Hesham went to work in the
family business at noho market
as soon as he was able to work.
Like his dad he is known
and much loved in the
neighborhood.
>> saeed took a little detour
from the family business.
He got his father's blessing to
try his hand in the fashion
industry which he studied at
city college before starting
work as a designer and stylist
for brands including shoe
palace and new era hat company
said has his own brand called
since birth and has styled
photoshoots for the nba all
star weekend said attributes
his family's resilience
resilience and strength
in adversity to their
palestinian heritage.
covid and post-covid the covid
and post-covid era have not
been easy for the family.
Their businesses continue to
feel the loss in tourism
and foot traffic.
But saeed says their people
have never been quitters.
Saeed and hisham.
We are grateful for you and the
floor is yours.
>> thank you, rafia.
>> hi everyone.
So I'm saeed and this is my
brother hisham and my mother
here.
I just like to say we're
definitely proud owners of a 50
year old business in the city
of san francisco which we all
know is not really easy to do.
My brother's store.
No, it was going on 26 years
now and we've always just took
pride in providing a real
corner store experience like
offering a book service where
people can pay us later or kids
around the neighborhood can
come and their parents will
come back later and give us the
bill.
My father just always built a
community space for everyone
even things like they can leave
their car keys and if we're
there early enough we'll move
it for street cleaning because
we know how annoying that is.
>> but yeah this the stores
and our businesses have always
been more than just a business
sometimes although it is our
second home sometimes it feels
like our first home because of
the time we spent and put ours
into.
When my father passed away my
brother and I took initiative
to keep his his legacy living
on.
>> I now have a two year old
son who's sitting in here.
>> you've probably heard him a
little bit but yeah, his name
is now sammy as well so I've
honored him in that space as
well and hope to one day pass
these businesses on to him
and continue the legacy.
Like rafael said, my main job
is being a stylist and I've
worked for companies like gazi
who just spoke earlier at
empire.
>> and it's been a great
experience just like ghazi I'm
just as proud as being a gazan
palestinian as I am being a san
franciscan.
You know there's not many of us
being born and raised
and staying and trying to push
through and build a community
around fashion or music or you
know, a healthy alternative
corner store where we're not
selling coca-colas and diet
cokes and cheetos.
We're trying to provide a
healthy alternative organic
produce alcopops and things
like that.
>> but yeah, I think that's all
I have for you guys and I
appreciate everything you guys
have done for me as a san
francisco city.
Thank you
.
>> >> all right.
>> so with that I think we go
to our 3 P.M. Special order.
>> MADAM Clerk.
Item 34 through 37
and subsequently all read items
38 through 41 items 34 through
37 comprise the hearing of
persons interested in the
determination of exemption from
environmental review under the
california environmental
quality act issued as a
categorical exemption by the
planning department on APRIL
5th, 2024 for a proposed
project at 1310 junipero serra
boulevard at which which
proposes the demolition of nine
maintenance and facility
structures and construction of
a 25 foot tall one storey
maintenance building
approximately 20,000 gross
square feet in size items 35
through 37 are the motions
associated with this ceqa
appeal.
Items 38 through 41 comprise
the hearing of persons
interested in the approval of a
conditional use authorization
for the project at 1310
junipero serra boulevard for
the construction of a 19,100
gross square foot one storey
accessory maintenance
and facility building for an
existing open area recreation
area use a tba.
>> items 39 through 41 comprise
the motions associated with
that conditional use appeal.
>> thank you MADAM Clerk and I
see supervisor melgar in the
queue.
>> thank you so much PRESIDENT
Mandell.
Man colleagues at this appeal
pertains to approach act
in district seven.
I am hoping to give at the two
parties a little more time to
come together and find some
common ground hopefully
and possibly and the appeals.
I move that items 34 through 41
be continued open to a date
certain on tuesday MAY 13th
2025.
>> all right.
Thank you.
Thanks to rose melgar, the
motion has been made
and seconded by supervisor
walton.
So I'm going to look to the
city attorney to make sure I
don't screw this up.
But I think what I would like
to do is open the public
hearings on items 34 and 38.
>> there's a motion to continue
those hearings which has been
seconded.
But before we can act on that,
we need to take public comment
on that motion to continue the
hearing.
>> so if anybody this is not
general public comment, this is
this is just public comment on
the motion for a continuance of
these two hearings.
>> anybody who wants to talk to
us about that, feel free to
line up.
>> oh GOD.
Or come forward.
>> thank you.
Good afternoon, supervisor.
I represent saint thomas moore
and the appeals for secure
and conditional use.
We asking for a continuance
today to try to negotiate a bit
more with the golf club.
We have just recently been able
to retain counsel to help us
in that we thought we had
counsel three weeks ago when he
had a trial come up so he had
to bail on us.
So we have a new attorney
patterson o'neill is
representing us and helping us
with our negotiations.
So we would greatly appreciate
another couple of weeks to get
those actions moving.
thank you very much, sir.
Good afternoon for california
state law and the three flags
that I see.
San francisco state level
government and the united
states of american government.
When I see liberally construing
the california state law to
then with the fine print
and word or digital word
environmental.
Department of homeland security
acknowledges our cellular able
fema.
>> she is the secretary of the
department of homeland
security.
Sir, I'm going to pause your
time for a moment.
>> this public comment is
specifically for these items.
It's the general public
comment.
Okay?
Yes, ma'am.
So if then board of supervisors
in san francisco with
environment to review so then
how far does the environment
go?
Arizona state university public
land management sun devil
1206669889.
The department of homeland
security.
Also fema acknowledges are
cellular able via emergency
management.
Official transcript 2016 fall
semester completed plans sun
devil 120666989.
So the department of homeland
security secretary as PRESIDENT
Sanford is PRESIDENT Is here
in san francisco and the
southern border with and how
far does the waterway go if
then the colorado river is I'm
also a source with the
department of california public
utilities environmental review
what it is as a colon within
environmental review and of all
the all I just want to say that
then NOVEMBER 19th, 2024 APRIL
15th 2025.
And then if then for seven
and the environmental
protection agency on the
southern border if that's the
southern border of mexico
within the waterways at the
border being polluted.
Thank you, ma'am.
That's why I came here today.
If it's as environmental.
>> thank you.
>> good afternoon, supervisors.
My name is david greenbaum on
the principal of st thomas more
school.
I'm a nearly 30 year educator
25 years I served in san
francisco unified school
district the last four at
visitation valley middle school
.
So currently as the principal I
am in support of the appeal for
us to have more opportunities
to negotiate with the south
school golf club who's who is
proposing to build a nearly
20,000 square foot shed about
20ft away from our preschool
after receiving an exemption
from sequoia?
Thank you everyone.
>> all right.
Appears that that is the end of
public comment on the
continuance.
The public comment is now
closed and colleagues, we have
a motion to continue these
hearings open to the MAY 13th
on.
>> all right same reopening
public comment on on the
hearings so all right so we can
continue it and we have a
motion open to continue these
hearings open to the MAY 13th,
2025 board of supervisors
meeting which I think
colleagues we can take without
objection.
So without objection these
appeal hearings and motion
motions are continued open to
MAY 13th 2025.
>> all right.
Let's go to roll call roll call
for introductions.
>> supervisor dorsey, your
first up to introduce new
business.
>> thank you, MADAM Clerk sir.
>> colleagues, I am today
introducing legislation to
improve and strengthen san
francisco's homicide reward
fund a critical tool for
advancing justice for the
victims and their surviving
loved ones of these horrific
crimes when they occur in our
city.
When the board of supervisors
first established the homicide
reward fund in 2016, the goal
was straightforward to
incentivize us cooperation
and solve homicides by offering
financial rewards for
actionable information.
But as reporting and city
records have shown, not a
single reward has yet been paid
out in more than a decade.
Meanwhile, families like that
of MISS Paulette brown whose
son aubrey armacost jr was
tragically murdered in 2006
continue to await justice that
has been too long denied them.
The heartbreaking truth is that
our reward program is currently
structured is failing to serve
the very families it was
created for.
Restrictive eligibility rules
requiring a conviction before
any payout disqualifying
disqualifying anonymous
tipsters and excluding
individuals with a criminal
record have created barriers
that discourage people from
coming coming forward.
The legislation I am
introducing today proposes
updates that would allow
rewards to be paid when
information leads to the filing
of criminal charges not just
convictions.
Enable anonymous tipsters to
receive rewards while
preserving their
confidentiality to end
automatic disqualification
based on a prior criminal
history and to ensure rewards
are not paid for knowingly
false information.
I would not be introducing this
ordinance today without the
persistent and courageous
advocacy of MISS Paulette
brown.
MISS Brown has attended
virtually every police
commission meeting for many
years.
Speaking with both
vulnerability and unflinching
clarity about the pain of
losing her son and the need for
change that she shares with so
many families who have waited
and are too often still waiting
for justice to be done, MS.
Brown has been relentless
in urging our city to do better
not just for her family but for
every family awaiting answers.
Today's legislation reflects
her extraordinary commitment to
justice and I want to
personally thank her for never
giving up.
I want to express my gratitude
as well to the san francisco
police commission for their
work on the resolution
and urging this board to
introduce this legislation
in particular its lead author,
former police commission vice
PRESIDENT Max carter oberstar.
By modernizing san francisco's
homicide reward policy, we can
better protect witnesses,
encourage cooperation, improve
clearance rates for unsolved
murders and most importantly
honor the memories of those we
have lost.
I respectfully ask for your
support and the rest I submit.
>> thank you.
Thank you.
Supervisor dorsey.
Supervisor and guardiola commit
summit.
>> submit.
Thank you.
Supervisor supervisor fielder
thank you, MADAM Clerk.
>> colleagues today I'm proud
to introduce a resolution
in strong support of assembly
bill 670 authored by assembly
member sharon quirk silva.
This bill is a critical step
toward recognizing the full
value of preservation within
california's affordable housing
strategies.
>> in san francisco we know
that present preserving
existing affordable housing is
just as vital as building new
units.
Our housing element makes that
clear.
It explicitly acknowledges
preservation as a core strategy
for meeting our housing goals
addresses shortages
and preventing displacement.
This isn't theoretical for us.
Programs like the small sites
program have already preserved
hundreds of units stabilizing
neighborhoods and supporting
low income tenants who might
otherwise be priced out of
their homes.
While we've had some important
successes including the recent
acquisition of three 2014
street in my district by the
san francisco community land
trust, we need to continue
investing in this important
strategy to scale the community
ownership movement.
8670 aligns with this goal by
allowing local governments to
count preservation efforts
toward their regional housing
needs.
>> allocation housing targets.
That's a smart, effective
change one that strengthens the
ecosystem of affordability
we've built here through
collaboration with nonprofits,
land trusts and tenants serving
organizations.
>> I urge your support for this
resolution and for 8670 which
honors what we've already shown
is possible in san francisco
that preservation is not only
practical.
It's essential.
I want to think planning
and study for being in touch
with my office.
Carl smylie with the as of
community land trust PRESIDENT
Killgore from my office for his
work on this resolution
and supervisors so
der
and moulton for co-sponsoring
and the rest I submit.
>> thank you.
Supervisor fielder supervisor
mahmood submit thank you.
>> supervisor randleman thank
you, MADAM Clerk.
I have one introduction today
which is a request for a
hearing on san francisco mta's
recently completed E.V.
Curbside feasibility study
and the path forward for public
ev curbside charging stations
in san francisco.
Our transportation sector
accounts for close to half of
san francisco's emissions.
>> and as I usually point out
when discussing this topic, the
most important thing we must do
to reduce those emissions is to
make public transportation
green, safe and reliable.
But I continue to believe that
making ev ownership and use
easier is an essential part of
the mix.
>> in JULY of 2023 I asked the
san francisco environment
department and mta to present
opportunities for implementing
a scalable ev curbside charging
program in san francisco.
The departments undertook that
work in two phases through the
curbside ev charging
feasibility study and pilot.
The first phase was the
feasibility study to analyze
case studies from other cities
like L.A. And new york that
have that already have robust
ev curbside charging programs.
The study also reviewed
charging technology
and standards jurisdiction
and regulatory considerations
curb management accessibility
requirements, grid capacity
and energy requirements, site
suitability, financial
feasibility and equity.
>> san francisco environment
S.F. Environment and mta engage
with community stakeholders.
Ev companies public works
and sfp uc to gather feedback
on how this program could be
rolled out in san francisco.
>> we anticipated a second
phase that would use the
findings and recommendations of
the study to begin installation
maintenance and operation of a
pilot curbside network.
In MARCH of last year I
introduced a resolution
supporting the efforts of the
departments to implement the
curve curbside ev charging
feasibility study and urging
the office of the mayor and
departments to leverage all
available funding sources to
implement the curbside ev
charging pilot this year.
Prior to passage of the
resolution the board held a
hearing where environment
and mta presented on their
framework for the pilot program
which was informed by what at
the time were preliminary
results of the feasibility
study.
The study was completed earlier
this year and identifies
opportunities for and barriers
to installation potential
potential installation sites as
well as recommendations for
governance of the program.
While the study was
in progress, mayor's breed
office got a mayor breed's
office got a head start on the
second phase.
Her team and now mayor luis
have been working with private
tv companies to work through
barriers toward installing
chargers.
>> they were able to
successfully install two last
week into both triangle san
francisco's first.
There should be more.
Yes.
Supervisor melgar we agree now
now that the study is complete
and the pilot is underway.
I'm calling for this hearing to
highlight the recommendations
of the study and determine next
steps for the city to implement
a long term ev curbside
charging program that
meaningfully moves us toward
our climate action plan
and E.V. Roadmap roadmap goals
of having 1760 publicly
accessible charging stations by
2030.
>> we'll be asking as have
environment mta public works
and the puc to present at our
hearing on JUNE 2nd and the
rest I submit.
>> thank you MR. PRESIDENT.
Supervisor melgar thank you so
much MADAM Clerk.
>> colleagues at this morning I
rallied with dozens of san
franciscans who understand that
unsafe streets in our city have
become a public safety
catastrophe over five years.
San francisco has seen nearly
100,000 traffic collisions.
These collisions have resulted
in more than 200 lives lost
in the cost to our city our
drivers as well as those who
walk, bike and take transit is
$2.5 billion over the past five
years according to the blr
report that I commissioned last
year.
Each fatal crash cost san
francisco drivers over $1.6
million.
But the costs aren't just
medical they're also economic
productivity.
They're the people who take
care of the injured for lost
wages and for any number of
things.
>> more than 22% of traffic
crash costs stem from lost
workplace and household
productivity.
Another 34% comes from property
damage.
Yet it has been more than 100
days since our city's prior
vision zero policy expired.
Just this past week there was
another terrible and avoidable
traffic incident resulting in a
death in district five.
While dangerous driving cost
the city billions.
Efforts to solve these issues
make up a minuscule portion of
the mta budget due to the
extent of this issue mta
traffic enforcement and safety
improvements are stretched very
thin as our speeds.
Not only will finding effective
ways to reduce crashes make our
cities and streets safer but it
will save billions of dollars
for everyday san francisco
and aid in our economic
recovery.
We don't have the time or the
money to stand by and let this
loss of life and loss of
taxpayer dollars can continue.
>> we need to fully fund safe
streets and we need to reinvest
in our vision zero goals.
This is a public safety issue.
>> this is why today I'm
calling for a hearing on the
bill a report that we have just
received a hearing on street
safety and economic recovery
for the city and county of san
francisco.
I want to thank my colleague
supervisor chan mahmud
and so
der as well as supervisor
field staff for joining me
earlier at the rally and for
your shirt shared commitment to
tackling this challenging
issue.
>> the rest I submit thank you
.
>> supervisor melgar.
Supervisor sartor.
>> colleagues.
Today I am introducing
alongside the mayor a
resolution approving the port
commission lease for 348
jefferson street.
This space will soon be chaska
reo a salvadorian restaurant
which hopes to be open by the
end of the year serving up
stews, soups purposes and fresh
fish to tourists and locals
alike.
This opening will soon join the
renowned barbecue space everett
and jones which will be opening
soon in the wharf and it is
wonderful to have these two
long vacant spaces activated.
We know of course though that
there is still much work to do
in fisherman's wharf and as fun
as it is to visit fisherman's
wharf I want us to always
remember too that it is a
economic hub for our city.
So as we speak of the budget
and speak of our city's
recovery, the wharf needs to be
strong as well.
Our office will continue to be
focused on all this work of
filling up empty storefronts,
activating public spaces,
investing in infrastructure
along the embarcadero and wharf
amidst rising sea levels
and expanding transit.
So the wharf is easier to get
to.
>> and the rest I submit.
Thank you.
Supervisor sutter supervisor
cheryl colleagues on today's
agenda is a resolution I
authored in support of assembly
bill 1181 authored by assembly
member matt haney.
>> hb 1181 requires the state
of california to update its
existing safety order regarding
firefighters personal
protective equipment mandating
that the state eliminate the
use of fast forever chemicals
in turnouts by 2027 absorbed
into the human body through
inhalation or contact.
These fast and static chemicals
have been shown to directly
increase the risk of cancer for
firefighter cause.
>> cancer is one of the leading
causes of death among
firefighters nationwide
and amounting to approximately
72% of line of death duties
in 2020 three.
>> here in san francisco our
fire department has lost over
300 firefighters to cancer
since 2006.
>> we must do all that we can
to better protect our
firefighters from long term
health implications and the
first step to doing so is
ensuring firefighting equipment
does not contribute or directly
cause higher cancer rates.
I'm grateful that
assemblymember haney is
bringing this change statewide
following the lead of san
francisco and supervisor chan
who led our a city effort to
ban fast and sfd equipment last
year.
And I'm additionally grateful
for supervisor chan as well as
supervisor sadr's
co-sponsorship in supporting
bringing this policy to the
state level.
>> I hope to have all of your
support in this effort and the
rest I submit.
Thank you.
Supervisor sheryl supervisor
walton.
>> thank you, MADAM Clerk.
I would like to be added as a
co-sponsor to item number 49
and the rest I submit.
>> thank you.
Supervisor walton shall be
done.
Supervisor chan thank you,
MADAM Clerk.
Colleagues, I'm introducing a
resolution formally declaring
this week as public works week
in san francisco and the tried
and true team of 1400 plus
employees including unions
members represent it by seiu
laborers international union of
north america 260 1ii petty
local 21 and many members of
the building and construction
trades and this is really the
entire team that a city
department that is a integral
part of the everyday lives of
our city residents workers
and visitors we really thank
them for their work day in and
day out.
I think this is one of the city
departments outside of our
first responders that actually
often works 24 seven.
So when we talk about saving
clean streets it really is that
public works workers really is
part of this work that's
sustaining the heart work for
our streets and all around.
So thank you to the staff
and unsung heroes at the public
works who works tirelessly 24
seven to support every corner
of the city to keep our city
clean, save resilience, build
affordable, assessable and the
rest I submit.
>> thank you.
Thank you supervisor chan.
>> supervisor chen thank you,
MADAM Clerk.
Colleagues, I would like to
join today's meeting
in memoriam of antonette jamil.
MS. Jamil was born on FEBRUARY
10th 1943 and passed on APRIL
20th third of this year.
>> I wish to honor her 82 years
and I shine a light on her life
.
>> antonette, also known as
tony MS. Tony was born on a
U.S. Navy ship on the coast of
nova called during world war
two.
>> she grew up in maine with
her mother alongside her
younger brother gregory.
>> she later married her
husband ali jamil and on their
honeymoon she saw elvis.
I was presently alive and was
quite special for tony as a
lifelong fan.
>> she dedicated her time to
her family volunteering at
schools and she was also a very
proud member of her incarnation
church catholic church
in glendale.
>> in her later years she moved
to palo alto to be closer to
her son michael daughter in law
annie and her grandkids oliver
and kate.
She enjoyed visiting san
francisco for her family
gathering and love having a
bowl of clam chowder in the
city to remind her childhood
in maine.
MAY her memory be a blessing.
Debra sized charles let me
thank you.
>> thank you, supervisor chin
and MR. PRESIDENT seeing no
names on the roster, that
concludes the introduction of
new business.
>> all right, let's go to
public comment.
>> at this time you MAY line up
on your right hand side of the
chamber.
We're taking public comment for
two minutes.
You MAY speak to the approval
of the board meeting minutes as
presented.
You MAY also speak to item 45.
That's the conference with the
city attorney pertaining to
existing litigation on matters
in which the city is a party
and that would be whether or
not to enter into the closed
session with the city attorney.
>> you MAY also speak to other
general matters that are not on
the on the agenda today but
must be within the board's
subject matter jurisdiction.
All other agenda content has
been reported out by an
appropriate committee where
public comment had occurred.
>> we're going to welcome our
first speaker.
Welcome.
>> thank you.
Peter alexander.
>> business as usual is over.
Comes now the iron rod of GOD.
>> the risen living lord lays
down the sword freezing the
west coast for dc and wall
street is but toast the freedom
strike of 40 nights and 40 days
opening the promised land by
this almighty command.
I am peter and I am commanding
so the protected racket of
trafficking women and children
on san francisco and oakland
ports is over.
The economy now frozen by my
warriors erosion.
The organized mega religions
have operated as the
anti-christ yet the unbeatable
power of jesus they could never
host.
For me it's the promised land
or bust in a warmongering world
of bloodlust.
>> which is why the patriarchs
of religion never wanted you to
hear what the master jesus
stated.
Those whose mouths are stained
with flesh and blood can never
understand the kingdom of
heaven and have no authority to
teach it.
I want to say I'm really glad
to see paulette brown and I had
a nice discussion with the
supervisor.
I'm going to finish with this.
Heroin, fentanyl
and trafficking have always
gone together.
The same dealers and slavers
can only operate with certain
city complicity.
Green beret DR. Jeffrey
macdonald has been down for 54
years after the bush regime of
heroin murdered his pregnant
wife and two daughters.
American veterans now remember
the battle of athens and there
is in fact a fentanyl lawsuit
in arizona where the former
attorney general is involved
and they are taking law
enforcement to task because
they know who the dealer was.
I support law enforcement.
Most of them are good people
but there's always been a 5%
corruption and that is now to
be erased as well.
I am peter.
I say you hear it.
So it is done.
>> thank you for your comment.
Welcome MISS Brown.
Thank you.
I like to use the overhead.
I'm here.
Concerning my son is always um
for unsolved homicides as well
as other other other unsolved
homicides that are here on this
paper from decade parts
and decades and decades.
I bring these names with me of
the perpetrators who were
involved in murdering my son
and then you have the the other
article about where former
mayor gavin newsom said I know
who killed her son, the D.A.
Who killed her son.
The police know who killed her
son.
But with no witnesses.
>> so if that's you can bring
it back to me.
If that's stopping people from
coming forth.
So I'm so glad that matt dorsey
just implemented this are just
brought to roll call this a
resolution on unsolved
homicides and and bringing ways
for tipsters to come forth.
So back in the day no one
wanted to come forth because
people were scared their lives
were involved, their lives
and their livelihoods were
involved because they didn't
want to say anything.
>> so this this resolution will
help other people to come forth
now and maybe someone will know
something about my son just as
well as mayor gavin newsom said
he knew.
So if he knows then guess who
else knows?
>> so maybe this can be brought
forth when this if this and I
pray that this resolution
passes that you know that it
get it get broadcast to to
tipsters and and people that
can testify even though
incarcerated.
>> I live in district five
and I still have to walk
and see where my son was
murdered.
And I pray that all the all of
you supervisors even my
district five supervisor
understand what I'm saying
and help with this resolution.
I am so tired of different
people.
>> but thank you for your
comment and welcome to the next
speaker.
Yeah I do agree with peter that
jeffrey mcdonald is innocent.
Our judicial system is so
screwed up.
I mean think about the j sixers
didn't do anything wrong.
They spent four years
in prison.
That's why they tucker carlson
got fired.
He's releasing all the footage
of the cops waving a man you
know, this whole
insurrectionist narrative is
all it's all lies and deceit.
>> now I would like to make a
comment about a very
interesting statement PRESIDENT
Trump made during easter how he
said the biggest event in all
of history is the death
and resurrection of the lord
jesus christ and it certainly
is.
It certainly is now.
He had no idea as cyrus said,
no idea that GOD was moving him
you know, a divine sentence is
in the lips of the king.
His mouth transgresses the knot
in judgment.
And when cyrus kate made this
declaration mission to restore
and build jerusalem, he started
off the greatest messianic
prophecy in the entire old
testament which said in daniel
nine that you had to have 77
year cycles or ten jubilees 490
years until christ would come
into this world.
And the reason why most people
don't realize that when trump
made this proclamation that it
was 50 jubilees from 1995 is we
don't adjust our chronology to
the baptism of christ.
It's very important to adjust
our chronology to the baptism
of christ in 50 jubilees from
cyrus's proclamation plus 360
of our months was when donald
j.
Trump made that proclamation.
Now jesus was about 30 years of
age because it was about the
30th jubilee.
In other words, seven years
later it would be the 30th
jubilee that was the 15th of
tiberius which corresponds to
28 ad on our calendar.
He had seven years.
It'll bring you to 35 A.D. For
the 490th.
>> thank you for your comment.
Jesus.
Just think about that.
>> we welcome our next speaker.
Really amazing you want to
talk?
>> good afternoon board of
supervisors.
My name is clara mobley.
I'm the director of advocacy at
the san francisco bicycle
coalition.
I'm here today on behalf of our
thousands of members and the
larger biking community to
support supervisor melgar his
request for a hearing and for
the city to prioritize as
in full defined safer street
infrastructure.
>> last year we had the highest
number of traffic fatalities
since our city committed to
reaching 0 in 2014.
>> traffic fatalities are the
most damaging result of unsafe
streets.
But what gets discussed less
are crashes that lead to
injuries.
This data shows that serious
injuries and fatalities on our
streets in total cause
immeasurable harm and pain
and also cost individuals
and the city as a whole
billions over time between 2018
and 20 2290 2799 traffic
crashes were reported on san
francisco streets.
That's an average of 18,560
crashes per year while
incomparable to the loss of
life.
>> this bel air report shows
the shocking financial cost of
unsafe streets.
>> the quick build process we
created in 2019 was meant to
fast track inexpensive safety
improvements using paint post
and signs and have been proven
to reduce collisions by 30%.
But we have seen many projects
delayed for months, sometimes
years while others are
implemented in less than three
weeks when there is political
support to do them 18,500
crashes and 42 people lost
their lives on our streets last
year.
These tragedies are
preventable.
The city has the tools and the
data to prevent them from
happening.
We need leadership from you
all.
We ask you all to work
collaboratively with city
departments to fast track these
tools like quick builds and the
biking and rolling plan in your
districts and to collaborate
across your districts.
We urge you to join supervisor
mel ga's call to fully invest
in our streets.
>> doing so will save lives
and thank you for your
comments.
>> welcome to the next speaker
.
>> hello supervisors.
My name is nadir amon.
I am a district one resident.
And today I am here on behalf
of the san francisco bay area
chapter of care the council on
american-islamic relations.
>> I am here to give comment on
the resolution recognizing
american muslim appreciate
asian and awareness month care
as a va would like to thank you
all for recognizing this month
and to thank supervisor bilal
mahmood for introducing this
resolution.
>> this is san francisco's very
first time acknowledging this
important occasion and nine
other bay area cities have
already done so this year.
>> the resolution is especially
meaningful as our muslim
communities have faced an
unprecedented and unrelenting
wave of islamophobia
and discrimination over the
last 18 months since the
genocide in gaza began.
>> care's 2025 civil rights
report documented 8658 total
complaints nationwide in 2024
the highest number of
complaints in this
organization's 30 year history
up 66% from 2020 to pre
genocide total.
>> I encourage you all to read
that report and learn about
what the american muslim
community is currently facing
and ask you to be publicly
vocal in condemning the
insidious anti-muslim anti-arab
and anti-palestinian hate that
is driving these complaints.
>> thank you.
>> thank you for your comments.
Welcome to our next speaker.
>> good afternoon PRESIDENT
Management and supervisors.
My name is marlena mackey
cabana.
I'm a campaign associate with
walk san francisco.
>> it's been 112 days since the
city's vision zero policy
expired.
City leaders MAY want to ignore
something that some view as a
failure but a lack of progress
on vision zero is not a failure
of the policy.
It's a collective leadership
failure.
When agencies work together
and solutions are applied at
scale and designed with safety
as the preeminent goal.
Vision zero works.
Cities around the world are
showing this.
in fact san francisco is
showing that vision zero works.
Look at the tenderloin
neighborhood where crash rates
and close calls have dropped
significantly because of
solutions that have been
applied at scale.
>> every street in the
tenderloin is 20 miles per hour
now every intersection has a no
turn on red and daylighting
zones.
There are pedestrian safety
zones at the majority of
intersections the widest
streets with the worst speeding
problems.
Have had lanes removed to calm
traffic and to keep drivers at
safe speeds.
>> there's a shiny new speed
camera on turk street.
That's what vision zero looks
like.
That's what we need everywhere.
It's up to you as our board of
supervisors to together with
mayor lurie and the heads of
every key agency
transportation, fire police,
public health and public works
to make vision zero a success
story.
But it can be more.
In fact, vision zero can be
part of our city's comeback
story because safe streets
don't just save lives.
Safe streets make san francisco
stronger.
A strong san francisco is one
where people get around their
neighborhood supporting their
local businesses and being part
of their community and are safe
doing so.
So please use your leadership
to get the city to adopt a bold
new vision zero policy and plan
now and then work relentlessly
to make it real with the
funding, accountability
and focus needed to succeed.
Thank you.
>> thank you for your comments
.
>> welcome.
>> my name is mahoney z body
and I'm here on behalf of item
47 and I wanted to personally
thank supervisor mahmood for
introducing this deeply
meaningful resolution as the
only muslim legislative aide
in city hall.
Standing here today feels both
humbling and profound.
This moment is not just
personal it's a long awaited
recognition of a community
whose presence in this city is
enduring beautiful
and essential american muslims
have long contributed to the
vitality of the city both
visible and unseen.
But often they do so without
acknowledgment.
Today we begin to change that.
>> recognizing APRIL as
american muslim appreciation
and awareness month is more
than a symbolic act.
>> it is a gesture of healing,
of belonging and of justice.
>> it is a simple but powerful
promise that our stories, our
labor and our identities matter
.
>> san francisco is home to
muslim educators, doctors,
lawyers, organizers and most
importantly small business
owners.
>> people who love the city
deeply even when it hasn't
always loved us back.
>> this resolution is a step
towards repairing that
disconnect.
It is a reminder that
visibility isn't about
performance.
It's about presence and the
power of being seen as a whole.
To my community this is for
you.
For the elders who've laid the
foundation and for the youth
who are daring to dream bigger.
>> and for everyone who has
ever questioned whether there
was space for them in places
like this.
>> there is I carry you with me
in every room that I enter
and every policy that I help
shape.
>> and I promise to continue
pushing until the halls of
power not only make room for us
but reflect us fully.
Thank you.
Thank you, mohandas for your
comments.
>> welcome to the next speaker.
Thank you for everyone there is
in this place today and last
year were for home raise a you
know home is a company they
care for many people in this
city and I would like to
express myself today to get
these we need additional
funding for better benefit.
We need many programs to
complete for our workers so as
a member for our union I see
that we need many things that
we like to see getting for
every single member for this
company.
>> I would like to give you an
example for why we do sector
giver.
We not only do a simple job we
are more than that and with our
funding we can make possible
many things for our community.
i would like to thank you for
this pay and remember that you
are the people for the people
we need you and thank you.
>> thank you for your comments
.
>> welcome to the next speaker
>> good afternoon board.
My name is jessica rodriguez
and I've been a home care
provider for over two years.
>> I'm here today to speak
in support of the home home
bridge program and tell you
about the important services we
provide.
I provide care to the most
vulnerable residents
and services including those
dealing with complex medical
issues including substance use
and mental health issues.
Without my care my clients
would not be able to live
independently in their own
homes.
>> it would be a disaster.
They wouldn't have anyone to
pick up after them when they
fall over or help take care of
their personal hygiene.
We are essential but our
current wages don't reflect the
valuable work that we do.
I shouldn't have to pay.
Live paycheck to paycheck.
We do work that no one else
wants to do and we need higher
pay in order to make sure san
franciscans most in need
continue receiving adequate
care.
We need better wages.
Our program needs additional
funding and that funding needs
to be invested in the workforce
so we can continue to live
and work in this area.
Thank you.
>> thank you for your comments.
Next speaker.
>> good afternoon.
Board of supervisors.
For the record my name is chris
ward klein and I also go by
sergeant klein.
The united states marine corps.
Earlier today I attended the
safe streets vision zero rally
summit.
Some of you were there and I
ask that we make this a key
strategy going forward.
Looking at the agenda today
there was funding a lot of
funding for hud starting
in JULY of this year.
There is one issue that that
housing many places funding
in jeopardy as they continue
inappropriately to charge
veterans disability as housing
income which is not allowed.
However that brings me to the
next point.
The city and the city attorney
can present a claim for
unclaimed funds from $5 billion
that will cover most of your
budgets for the next three
years.
That will cover most of the
cuts that you have for all your
nonprofits that will give you
money for your vision zero
funding just about everything
plus a lot of citizens in the
city will have 10 to 15,000
paychecks that were owed to
them because we as citizens
and the city and county of san
francisco was victimized by
state sponsored terrorism.
So I urge each of you to get
with the mayor, the city
attorney to present this claim.
This is not three years down
the road.
This is as soon as you put the
claim in there's a judge
waiting to give this money to
san francisco.
It's not any strings attached.
It's unclaimed damages.
This isn't money that you have
to follow a certain PRESIDENT
Former PRESIDENT, current
PRESIDENT.
>> it will be san francisco
money five billion dollars that
you could have within days or
weeks.
So again, I urge everyone
in this chamber to reach out to
the mayor and the city
attorney.
They know exactly what I'm
talking about.
They're hesitant and I don't
understand why.
Thank you.
Have a great day everyone.
>> thank you for your comments.
Next speaker hi, my name is
mohammad yasir.
I'm a proud muslim union leader
public servant and a community
organizer.
Let me provide some details
about it.
I'm an only muslim in my bureau
in fact an only muslim on the
whole floor 49 sunday night
and I'm an only muslim elected
chapter PRESIDENT For the labor
unions in san francisco.
It's not easy to make your way
and rise if you belong to an
immigrant, especially a muslim
immigrant family.
We muslims are contributing to
this beautiful city on every
level.
People who know me, they know
me and my team work day
and night out in the field to
make the city safer
and cleaner.
I want to thank you supervisor
bilal mahmood for introducing
the resolution for american
muslim appreciation awareness
month.
With the help of council on
american-islamic relations
and I want to say thank you to
the board of supervisors for
supporting it.
It really matters for the
marginalized communities like
us to get acknowledged
and recognized.
Thank you very much.
>> thank you for your comments.
Next speaker.
>> good afternoon supervisors.
My name is niles shaker.
I'm the resident imam of san
francisco muslim community
center.
We're located in district 11 on
mission street.
Supervisor chan district
and I'm here to lend my voice
to the voices that have come
before me and also those who
will follow me on the adoption
of this resolution as
introduced by supervisor bala
mahmood.
Thank you.
Supervisor mahmood.
As a member of a class of
people who have actually been
muslims of the indigenous
muslims who in this country
since the atlantic slave trade
and those who have been in the
city of san francisco since the
early 1930s are our resolution
the resolution today the
consideration for this
resolution is very important.
We've had a presence in the
city for a long, long time
and we've also helped deal with
many, many issues going back to
the days of the civil rights
struggle even muslims dealing
with joining people then to
fight for rights for people who
had gone unrecognized for so
long because of their quote
unquote second class centers.
Now as muslims we do not think
or even dare to think that we
are a whole any position less
and less than anyone else.
And we would like to ask
and then give you and thank you
for your consideration for this
to adopt this resolution.
>> thank you.
Thank you for your comments.
>> welcome to the next speaker
.
>> >> good afternoon everybody.
My name is required and I'm
here to give a public comment.
Being american and muslim
in san francisco is not shy of
a disappointment growing up
in mosques around the city
specifically the ones down the
street.
Jones nor to read places of
religion, love and community
are dirty.
They are run down and often
times have not have often times
extra security measures just to
get into the building.
This is not how I want to view
the house of GOD.
Growing up and attending
abraham lincoln high school
over in the sunset district, my
hijab was pulled off and I was
bullied alongside other peers
for wearing clothing that are
considered modest in a city so
welcoming and open to embracing
diversity and each other's
differences as being muslim is
still something to be feared
even when I made the decision
to wear hijab I was discouraged
and I was shamed as if I wanted
to wait until I was more
established in the workforce to
put it back on.
>> be there and these are words
from muslims themselves.
In this country we are shamed
to be muslim and that's not how
I want future generations to
feel.
I want them to feel proud
and to feel included by their
city not to be bullied, not to
be shamed or have difficulty
in the workforce.
The good times are their time.
I stand in support of the
american people.
I appreciate in awareness.
>> thank you.
Thank you for your comments.
>> welcome to the next speaker
.
>> alaikum and good afternoon
everyone.
My name is radwan and I'm here
today as a proud muslim woman.
I'm azhar, someone who has
spent years serving san
francisco's family as an
educator and advocate and a
neighbor.
>> I want to thank supervisor
mahmood and this board for
introducing the american muslim
appreciation awareness month
resolution.
>> it's not just the
recognition it's just and it
means that we as american
muslim belong in this city
and that our contribution
matter.
I want to speak from heart as a
muslim woman.
I have experienced
discrimination firsthand.
I have been threatened at my
own workplace.
My place is for service simply
because I wear this I wear my
hijab.
>> and perhaps the hardest part
of all is this I had to teach
my children how to respond when
someone calls them a terrorist
think about it and instead of
teaching just teaching your son
or your kids how to ride a bike
or they have to do their
homework, I have to prepare
them to defend to defend their
humanity.
>> but until we show up we give
back.
>> we build our community
and we keep going because of
our faith.
>> our faith teaches us to
stand for justice.
>> our love for this city runs
deep.
This resolution doesn't erase
the pain but it matters.
It tells us our children that
they are not alone.
They don't need to hide who
they are to be accepted that
san francisco sees them.
>> honor them and respect them
and protects them.
Thank you for this moment of
truth and hope.
>> thank you.
Thank you for your comments.
>> welcome to the next speaker
.
>> thank you.
My name is abdullah.
I am immigrants rights
commissioner but I'm speaking
on my behalf and I'm a resident
of the supervisor washroom
through chinatown community.
I'm center I'm representing not
less than 300 families in the
tenderloin but as a mother
and a community advocate and a
son and a muslim woman I
strongly support resolution to
officially recognize APRIL 2025
as an american muslim
appreciation and awareness
month in san francisco.
Thank you supervisor plaid for
introducing this.
Every day our community wakes
up to their new executive
orders that often echo the fear
and the trauma we experienced
during trump's first term when
we were called every name
in the book simply for being
muslim.
These actions reopen wounds
and remind us that our
visibility and dignity are
still on the line.
California and especially the
bay area is home to over a
million muslims from diverse
backgrounds.
Like so many immigrant
community who are hardworking,
dedicated and deeply invested
in the well-being of the state.
But we want more than just hard
work.
We want to be seen here.
And value.
Thank goodness under the
leadership of advocates of
dedicated advocates,
supervisors like bilal nine bay
area adopted this resolution.
Now san francisco had the
opportunity to become the 10th
city to stand with us.
Thank you.
And if you don't mind another
colleague was here before
and but she missed it.
Can I say her words?
>> I'm sorry, ma'am.
I'll pass your time.
Can you repeat that?
>> I had a hard time hearing
what you said.
Someone was here before and she
had like two lines to say but
she got to leave for her work.
Can I say it on behalf of.
>> you have 28 seconds left.
Absolutely.
>> I promise I will.
Good morning.
My name.
My name is jane chee and I am
proudly served the people of
san francisco for 28 years
currently as the security
operation intelligence manager
at S.F. Empty.
I wanted to express my deep
gratitude for this resolution
recognizing muslim appreciation
and awareness month at the
muslim public servant.
This acknowledgment means a
great deal.
It affirms the contribution of
muslim employees across city
department and the vibrant
muslim communities that helped
shape san francisco.
>> thank you for taking this
opportunity.
>> thank you kindly.
Welcome to the next speaker.
>> oh everybody.
My name is amin sheikh.
I reside in district seven
and I'd like to thank the board
of supervisors for for adopting
the resolution hopefully to
recognize the muslim
appreciation and awareness
month.
>> it serves as an opportunity
to increase understanding
and address the challenges
faced by american muslims
including discrimination
and hate crimes.
As we observe this month we
invite our san francisco
community to learn more about
the rich heritage culture
and faith of american muslims.
Let this be a time to celebrate
diversity to stand firmly
against discrimination
and continue building bridges
rooted in respect unity
and shared humanity.
>> thank you.
Thank you for your comments.
>> welcome to the next speaker.
Good evening and thank you for
giving me the opportunity to
talk.
>> I'd like to speak in support
of the resolution for the
muslim appreciation
and awareness month.
>> this is a very much
appreciated resolution and it's
hard to thank the sponsors of
this resolution which I hope
will be adopted.
It speaks volumes for us our
muslim community.
I am the board PRESIDENT Of
these selfless groups.
Let me school.
We had our students coming.
They were here earlier on.
Unfortunately they had to go
back to school because it was
pick up time to go back home.
But they all were excited,
happy and encouraged to see
this such a resolution being
being put on the table.
And it has two major impacts.
The first one is that it shows
that the city the higher ups
are like just take a stand
against bigotry, hateful speech
and acts and deter any anything
of that sort coming in the
future.
The second thing is for our
students, you know, to feel
they're safe and empowered,
they are motivated and they
like really feel they're safe
and and have a bright future
in in the city and in this
country.
>> so thank you so much.
Please adopt it.
thank you.
>> thank you for your comments.
Welcome.
Speaker bismillah aleikum.
>> welcome to the iowa
pubblicata.
My name is jason ross brown.
I'm a district nine resident.
I also have a small business
in district nine in the
redstone building.
>> I do fundraising for
nonprofits in the city.
>> oh my gosh.
I was so happy when I got the
call last night to come to this
building to celebrate something
positive for muslims.
Extremely happy.
Thank you.
I really don't have that much
to say other than to get you
already you are in the bay
area.
>> we have an amazing muslim
population here.
I invite you all to really get
to know us.
We have 250,000 muslims in the
bay area and I really need you
to know about this one
organization called aleph dot
built the young muslims are
here in san francisco.
They had a startup fund like a
founders conference with 600
young muslims in san francisco
at fort mason in SEPTEMBER
2025.
They didn't ask permission.
They came they take up space.
They are building companies.
They are like I don't know.
>> I'm completely amazed.
Supervisor mahmud I'm amazed
that you're here.
I'm just hopeful.
I'm a new yorker that has been
in this very anti-black
anti-muslim place for about 20
something years and the tide is
changing and I'm really happy.
>> supervisor walton, thank you
for your work as my supervisor
.
>> field for all of you.
I don't know everybody's name
but I was really on the other
side of like feeling kind of
pessimistic about this city
about it being a cultural brand
but not a cultural reality.
It seems like it's changing now
.
>> really?
Really.
Thank you so much.
Have a great day.
Thank you so much for your
comments.
Welcome to the next speaker.
>> hello.
Good afternoon supervisors.
My name is nancy you law I am
on behalf of chinatown history
and culture association and the
chinese way will workers
history center to thank you for
supporting for for for doing
this for us so I extend my
deepest gratitude to do some of
cisco para supervisors for this
profound recognition today we
stand in honor of the thousands
of chinese railroad workers who
labored as to build a
transcontinental railroad an
achievement that transformed
the infrastructure of the
nation and unite the country
from coast to coast.
This recognition is more than a
tribute to their preservation
but hard work and it is
affirmation that their
contributions are in a central
part of american history to
recognize their effort is to
acknowledge acknowledge that
that labor dedicate ocean
and resilience shaped the
destiny of the nations their
journey was filled with
challenges harsh conditions,
little pay and discriminations
yet their determination never
wavered.
Their contribution should not
just be remember but they
should inspire of future
generations.
This motion stands as a
powerful test the testimony
that dedicate dedication
and perseverance of never be
forgotten.
It sends a message to young
people, to young generation
across our community.
Your measure, your contribution
matters, your history matters
and the work you have done to
build a better america.
Meadows and beyond.
>> thank you supervisor chan
and also provisos.
Hopefully you can adopt this
resolution.
Thank you very much.
>> thank you.
Thank you for your comments.
>> welcome commissioner steven
lee I got I was going to say
that I want to support
and thank you for the
resolution of chinese railroad
workers.
I am the founder of the chinese
railroad workers memorial
project in 2015 at the
anniversary of the hundred
and 50 year transcontinental
railroad, we built a statue a
monument for chinese railroad
workers and that was because we
wanted a visual symbol so that
the little kids can remember
who helped built this country
with the irish and everybody
all the other immigrants.
And so these resolutions do
help continue with the with the
education of their youth to let
people remember who the chinese
railroad workers were and of
course standing behind all the
immigrants that are working
in chinatown and all the
districts in san francisco.
Thank you very much.
All your supervisors thank you.
Thank you for your comments.
Welcome to the next speaker.
>> I'm sorry.
>> good afternoon supervisors.
I'm peter warfield, executive
director, library users
association library users
2004@yahoo.Com and P.O. Box
170544 san francisco,
california 94117-0544.
In these days it's important to
appreciate and support all the
good that public libraries
provide our society
and individual roles and we
certainly want to support
and urge you to fully support
our public library and others
as necessary.
Tonight is the premiere of a
document entry called free for
all on kqed channel nine at
10:00.
And it's got a lot of very good
material about the history of
libraries and are well worth
watching.
Unfortunately not all libraries
are in all ways living up to
library ideals and principles.
For example, in san francisco
the privacy of patron patrons
and their confidentiality of
their records has been more
and more eroded including
in ways that were strongly
opposed by the american civil
liberties union of northern
california and electronic
frontier foundation.
It has also cut off after hours
wi fi at a single branch
because the neighbors and a
supervisor were concerned about
the gathering of one particular
population homeless people
after hours.
These are just a few examples
of library our library not
following the ideals
and basically principles
and ethical considerations of
libraries that are supposed to
serve the public.
I would also say more and more
materials are only available to
people who have certain
technological access.
We want excellent libraries
everywhere and when necessary
improvement when the
performance MAY fall short.
>> thank you.
Thank you for your comments.
Before the next speaker if you
are here to provide general
public comment please step
forward.
Otherwise this gentleman will
be the last speaker.
Welcome sir.
>> good evening.
My name is richard dusty
peterson.
I'm here to briefly talk about
the ironies of the city and the
onus that is placed on small
businessmen going through the
rules of the city to find out
the address of the owner of
certain property mainly the
properties owned by johnny.
>> I've who's probably more
famous in san francisco than
anyone except for mayor lurie
and certain others.
>> and I mailed something to
him and was returned
undelivered.
It was just simply a couple of
card decks that had been
created that I created through
my company and it was returned
with no forwarding address
provided by the postal service.
>> I looked up the postal
service and the postal service
does have a address for only
service that you can pay for.
But how does this small
ss pay for a space of
good for a large magazines
and subscriptions or people
with large entities with lots
of money to be able to provide
whatever they need provide?
>> does this come up as a shop
and taking up the desk here?
Yes.
>> oh I got to move it down
some more.
But the owners of small
business if you pay the post
office a fee they will provide
certain numbers to you zone
numbers.
And it's very, very expensive.
How does the small business man
get it?
There is a data san francisco
which provides a lot of data
about the city and their
services.
But there's nothing that would
help provide the small
businessman get these things
without paying.
>> sorry.
Thank you for your comments.
>> all right, MR. PRESIDENT.
>> all right.
Public comment is now closed.
MADAM Clerk, let's skip over
the closed session for now
and call it at the end of the
agenda.
Let's go to our four adoption
committee reference agenda
items 46 through 52 items 46
through 52 were introduced for
adoption without reference to
committee.
A unanimous vote and unanimous
vote is required for adoption
of a resolution on first
reading today.
Alternatively, a member MAY
require a resolution on first
reading to go to committee.
>> supervisor mahmood PRESIDENT
Elect to request to sever item
47.
Great.
Supervisor melgar.
>> thank you.
I'd like to request to sever
item 50 and also be added as a
co-sponsor to item 47.
>> all right.
I don't see anyone else so.
>> MADAM Closer chen.
Oh.
Supervisor chen.
>> can I also request to be
added as a co-sponsor to item
2504 355 to firefighters 49.
>> yeah.
Thank you.
Number 14 I think I think I've
been added to that but add me
to 46.
>> sorry.
49.
Okay.
You're on it, MR. PRESIDENT.
>> all right.
Great.
So that leaves 46, 48, 49, 51
and 52.
>> all right.
So on those items, MADAM Clerk,
can you please call the roll
supervisor dorsey dorsey I
supervisor engardio engardio I
supervisor fielder filter I
supervisor mahmood mahmood i
supervisor mandel min mandel
woman I supervisor melgar
melgar I supervisor sardar
sardar I supervisor cheryl
cheryl I supervisor walton
walton I supervisor chan chan I
and supervisor chen chen I
there are 11 eyes.
>> thank you MADAM Clerk.
Without objection the
resolutions are adopted and the
motions are approved.
>> and then can you please call
item 47?
>> item 47 this is a resolution
to recognize the month of APRIL
2025 as american muslim
appreciation and awareness
month in the city and county of
san francisco.
Profesor mahmood.
Colleagues, as a
muslim-american I want him to
speak on the resolution of the
city and county of san
francisco celebrating american
muslim appreciation
and awareness month enriched by
the unparalleled diversity of
its residents, san francisco
county takes great pride
in supporting individual
religious freedoms and is
strengthened by the many varied
religious, political
and cultural traditions
and contributions of its
diverse populations including
those the practice islam.
>> california alone is home to
nearly 1 million american
muslims and today millions of
american muslims both
immigrants and native born
represent a wide range of
ethnicities, languages
and beliefs united by their
shared faith and civic
engagement.
>> our city is home to muslim
institutions that teach values
of compassion, dignity and love
such as the islamic center of
san francisco.
Masjid eltahawy the al sabeel
masjid nura aslam in san
francisco, muslim community
center which also provide
educational enrichment services
programs for youth and foster
principles of equality, justice
and peace.
We know that under this climate
our diverse communities are
under attack.
>> the council on
american-islamic relations
received 8658 complaints of
anti-muslim bias nationwide the
highest in its 30 year history
.
It is our duty as elected
officials to uplift our diverse
communities and to fight
against discrimination,
xenophobia and hate.
>> and continue to share that
we will support our first
amendment rights to practice
religion freely.
San francisco has always been a
hub for immigrants and refugees
a beacon of diversity.
So thank you to all the
community members who came out
today to demonstrate my
speaking during public comment
on this important item.
And thank you to my colleagues
for your support as well.
>> thank you.
Supervisor mahmood.
I think we can take this item.
Same house, same call.
>> without objection the
resolution is adopted and MADAM
Clerk, please call item 50.
>> item 50.
This is a resolution to
recognize APRIL 2025 as
parkinson's awareness month
in the city and county of san
francisco to raise awareness
and support for those affected
by parkinson's disease.
>> supervisor melgar thank you
PRESIDENT Mailman and thank you
to supervisor sauder and cheryl
for your co-sponsorship.
APRIL is parkinson's awareness
month.
As many of us know especially
those of us who have loved ones
who are suffering from this
terrible disease parkinson's is
a chronic neurodegenerative
disorder.
It is the second most common
neurodegenerative disease
in the world after alzheimer's
.
>> parkinson's disease now
affects almost a million people
in the united states and more
than 10 million people across
the world.
Almost 90,000 people in the
U.S. Are diagnosed every year
and by 2030 it is expected that
the number of people with this
disease in the U.S. Will rise
to 1.2 million.
This disease can severely
affect a person's quality of
life which puts incredible
strain on both those affected
by the disease and their loved
ones.
>> currently there's no
definitive lab or imaging task
can diagnose this disease
and symptoms can vary from
person to person which makes
getting an accurate diagnosis
critical.
>> given the widespread nature
of the season and the
increasing number of cases, it
is essential that we educate
the public about the symptoms
and the diagnosis methods.
We are so fortunate to have one
of the best institutions here
in san francisco ucsf at the
forefront of this research.
Now more than ever we should
support our medical
professional professionals, our
scientists and our researchers.
I also want to acknowledge the
world the work of caregivers
and volunteers that are working
tirelessly to improve the life
of people living with
parkinson's.
There are treatments that can
help symptoms but unfortunately
as of now not a cure yet.
>> I want to emphasize that
there's no easy screening
process for raising awareness,
education and support.
So it is critical that people
get early diagnosis
and treatment.
I must apologize that there was
one word missing from the
resolution which I must now
correct.
The word not was missing in the
whereas clause on page two to
lines three and four it should
read whereas a specific library
imaging test can not diagnose
parkinson's disease and I will
be making an addition to
clarify that making it
essential for patients to know
about existing diagnosis
methods.
So I would like to make a
motion to make that amendment.
MADAM Clerk and a colleague
will second and again thank you
for your support.
>> all right.
So we have a motion from
supervisor melgar and a second
from supervisor fielder and I
think colleagues we can take
that motion without objection
and then MADAM Clerk, can you
please call the roll on the
amended item four actually.
You don't need to call the
roll.
We can take the amended item
same house, same call without
objection the resolution is
adopted.
>> okay.
And MADAM Clerk, I think that
takes us to our closed session.
Please call item 45.
Item 45 is the board of
supervisors to convene
in closed session for a
conference with the office of
the city attorney with the city
attorney for the purpose of
conferring with or receiving
advice pertaining to existing
litigation matters in which the
city is a party.
There are various titles here
but pertaining to anticipated
litigation the city MAY
initiate as plaintiff to
challenge acts and actions by
the federal government.
>> thank you, MADAM Clerk.
>> we're going into closed
session.
So MR. PRESIDENT, we will ask
the public to leave the chamber
and we will prepare the chamber
for the closed session.
>> great
.
>> S.F. Gov tv san francisco
government television
and cisco county.
You're watching san francisco
rising with chris manners.
Today's special guest is eibar
S.R.O..
>> hi, I'm chris manners
and you're watching san
francisco rising the show
that's I-about restarting,
rebuilding and reimagining our
city.
Our guest today is ibsa taro.
He's the director of airport
operations at san francisco
international airport.
MR. Starrett, welcome to the
show.
Good to be with you, chrisar.
Thank you for coming out to sfo
and joining us today.
Well, it's nice to see you.
Let's start by talking about
how the airport has recovered
post-pandemic both in terms of
passenger traffic and the
number of carriers here
and actually the number of
destinations that you're
serving as well.
Yeah, it'sf really exciting.
You know, we've come out strong
out of the crisis and now we're
back in full swing.
New carriers air premier
starlux porter great new
destinations.
So we have a lot more to our
mix now.
Nvegood to see our legacy carriers
returning as well to some
really wonderful destinations
that are now returning and and
people are loving it.
You know, we'rere at 110% of our
pre-covid international level
now which is exciting and that
is even without the full
recovery of chinana yet.
So we're anticipating more
flights to china but the
recovery is well underway
and it's exciting to see how
busy our terminals are these
days.
That's great.
So now what renovation or
expansionee plans are currently
underway or slated for the near
future for sfo?
>> right.
A lot of exciting programs.
We did suspendnd some of the work
because of covid and now we're
back at full swing and our
capital program and recently
finished the final phase of
harvey milk terminal one
and I'll tell you talk about
setting a standard in passengeral
experience it is amazing
and it's exceeded all my
expectations and so finishing
harvey milk terminal one was a
priority for us and now we'reng
working on terminal three west
and you know that's one of the
last terminals thatow has yet to
receive the sfo in touch with
that really focus on the
passenger experience of
terminal three west.
Incredibly exciting that
project has kicked off and will
take the next four and a half
years to complete and then we
have a lot of infrastructure
investment as well
that we're
doing.
It's all part of an $11 billion
investment over the next 5 to 7
years 8 billion in our
facilities in our terminals
and the 3 billion in our
infrastructure.
Really exciting also too
implement projects like our our
new wastewater system and our
reclaimed water most
importantly where we'll be able
to reuse a lot of the water
that were treated
here at sfo.
That actually brings me right
on to my next question which is
you know, the san francisco
international airports prettyst
globally well known for both
the environmental
and sustainability initiatives.
Could you elaborate on those a
little for us?
Yeah.
You know, we set
really
aggressive goals.
You know, we set a000 goal
and this is zero net energy
zero greenhouse gas emissions
and zero waste and you know we
have had that as one of our
primary values for, you know,
over a decade now a and we've
made great progress.
Exciting to see our energy use
has gone down by 15% from our
2013 baseline.
Our water use is down 20%
and our greenhouse gas
emissions down 38% from our
1990 baseline and that is about
the investment we make and the
quality
of facilities we build
and really helps reduce energyy
consumption and heating
and cooling loads.
And so all of those things gog
into it when we make these
decisions to do this major
investments is what is thatma
quality that benefits the
environment.
When we designto
and plan these
buildings and so it's really
exciting and it's wonderful to
see the success we're having.
And then I think about the
future and and sustainable
aviation fuel and we've leaned
in since 2018 to show
leadership in the advancement
of sustainable t aviation fuel.
Sfo will be the airport to
deliver the most sustainable
aviation fuel of any airport
in the world.
This year and next year.
so we're incredibly excited
about that as well.
So now
there's a huge workforce
at sfo that an undoubtedly hasub
an impact on both the local
and regional economies.
Can you sort of just address
that for me for a second?
Yes.
You know, we are the largest
job center in san mateo county
and we employ 40,000 people at
sfo and we contribute about $40
billion to the regionale economy
in terms of business revenues.
There's about 150,000 jobs that
rely upon the successful
operations of our airport.
So it is really a tremendous
contributor to our economy.
It's about our operations but
it's also about our
construction programsth.
And I talked a little bit about
the investment we've made
and we've been investing in our t
facilities for so many years.
You know, I've been here three
decades and we've been under
construction that whole time
almost and the job creation
through the construction
programs has been really
meaningful for well-paying f
trades or trades work
and internships has always been
a priority for us and this year
I met with our interns
yesterday and we had over 100
interns this year supporting
the sfo team so we're really
appreciative of the support we
gett and the labor that's
available to sfo.
>> that's great.
So finally what technological
advancements are sort of on the
cards that will enhance both
passengerad experience
and airport operations?
>> you know in many people
don't know you know the history
of innovation is long at sfo
in fact 1959 we were the first
airport to actually have jet
bridges and then you think
about kind of the disruption
that's happened particularly
with uber and lyft and we were
the first airport to permit
their operations and now we're
making $50 million a year off
of uber and lyft operations.
And when you experience our
terminals we're advancing
technology things like
automated screening lanes
and what a different experience
that is now for people going
through the checkpoint and then
our independent carrier system,
our t bag system that is also the
latest technology and the first
in the U.S. To have an
independent carrier system.
And now if you travel through
harvey milk terminal one when
you're exit and we have our two
exit portals so yeah the
innovation has just really been
tremendous particularly as we
develop new facilities.
But you know for us too it's
about our operation and you
know for the future there's
exciting new developments
happening.
We have recently implemented a
ground based augmentation
system called our g based
systemro and this is technology
that improves the arrival rate
of aircraft at sfo and it
allows for development of
arrivals that benefit
communities by higher
elevations by offsetting out
over the water.
And so we invested in that for
a community benefit for noise
and quality of w life but also
you know, for delays because
delays are also a community
benefit as people know when we
get poor weather and traffic
starts coming in after
midnight, it's it's an impact
to our community.
And so you know, we're
investing in our facilities
and investing in our operations
.
We now have ourur airport
integrated operations center
underway.
That is this aggregation of a
lot of technologies to give us
much better real time situate
national awareness on our
operation and being able to
adjustre adjust our operation to
address congestion, you know,
roadside congestion, checkpoint
congestion,, gate congestion
gives us much better awareness
of where we are and and other
things we could talk about that
that are exciting as well.
What aboutbo air taxis?
It's an exciting innovation we
are involved in.
We are working with the
industry on what that might
look like into sfo and we're
preparing for the future of air
taxis and one of our big
initiatives is to engage the
broader region in the
development.
You knowhe we all have to have
policies that address the air
taxi innovation and so we're
conducting a study with ucc
berkeley's transportation
center and engaging the
industryry b, engaging decision
makers and the region
in helping develop policies
that will give us a frameworkev
for addressing the air taxi
innovation as it starts to comeam
online in the next several
years.
Well thank you MR. Satara for
sharing your vision and your
creative ideas for san
francisco international
airport.
S.U.We really appreciate the time
you've given us here today.
Thanks chris.
It's been my pleasure.
And that's it for this episode.
We'll be back withve another one
shortly for S.F. Gov tv I'm
chris matters.
Thanks for watching and you're
watching golden gate adventures
withn lightweight horses all
seasonad.
>> in this episode is exploring
golden gate hong kong.
>> hi I'm michael baltazar
and you're watching golden gate
adventures, a show thatal
highlights san francisco's
urban outdoors.
Today we're in golden gate
park.
We're going to highlight a few
of the activities they have
here.
Y
first up archery.
>> let's
shoot from carrow
road.
We're here at 47th and fulton.
The archery range here at
golden gate park and I'm here
with my 4he g friend jim who is an
expert at archery.
He's going to give us a few
tips.
First off, let's see.
I think safety is
reallyy
important.
That's an excellent idea.
soso number one, just with
anything like archery, you want
to make sure that everything is
pointed at the
s target.
So once we have an arrow on the
bow we wouldn't want to point
it at somebodyt.
>> we would always want to makes
sure that what we're doing is
pointed down range w toward the
target.
So number two is the number one
is for mostly for protecting
other people.
Protecting yourselff is
important too.
So you always want to use a tab
or a glove like the one you're
wearing foror finger protection.
When drawing and releasing the
string also our armed guards
keep the string from hitting
our arms on the release.
>> what we're using todayay is a
very modern and contemporary
recurve bow.
Sorv compound long bows re
curves.
They're asian asiatic bows
mongolian japanese.
Turkish.
Syrian.
Very distinctive shapes.
>> totally different flavors of
archery just based on that.
>> let's try this.
All right.
>> so archery is all about
accuracy as you try to hit the
target.
The sports reads go way back to
hunting in battlefields but
today it's evolved into
something recreational
and competitive.
This range is in a chill spot
tucked into a peaceful wooded
area on the west end of the
park.
>> this is a lot of fun guys
whether you're just starting>>
out or already a pro it's the
perfect place to practice.
There are well-maintained
target bales at different
distances all surrounded by
tallll trees and lush greenery
creating a calm atmosphere.
That was awesome.
I think what we're guys you're
better than that, right?
>> we're going to go the ranges
run by volunteers and it's
totally free to use but you'll r r
need to bring your own gear or
rent some nearby.
Locals and tourists love it
whether they're honing their
skills
or just wanting to try
something different outdoors
in the city.
Feoh that was a bad one.
Archery can be very humbling
and not too bad.
This one one's a little high
because that was my second
shot.
I couldn't really I didn't
really feel that one as well.
But once I got it honed in I
think I got one in the ten.
Let's go that way.
Oh
wow.
>> farther back.
Oh, left again.
Just left.
Oh, just to the left.
That's the right elevation.
Right.
I saw that.
You got it.
Okay.
Glacier I visualize it.
Yeah, you're right.
The last it oh, it's so close I
look so get in the air.
All right, next time.
that's why I got to come out
here practice.
That was very exhilarating.
I love archery, man tim, why do
you love archery?
What's not to like?
You can do it.
We just did, which was spend
time together exploring it
and working on it.
You can also have aan blast going
off into the woods by yourself.
So all of the you know this
range any range you can do it
with friends you can do it by
yourself.
You can get the experience you
want fromur it.
There's a lot ofk fun and I
thank you for being my buddy on
this archery.
That's my pleasure.
It's good to see you, mike.
Okay now we're going to go
rowing.
>> now we're at the blue heron
boathouse.
We can geteon two different kinds
of boats.
There's actually a paddle boat
and a rowboat's.
I think we're going to go get a
rowboat.
Let's go get on the lake.
>> time to row a boat.
Boat.
Boat surrounded by greenery.
>> this manmade lake is a nice
little escape from the busy
city t.
The key thing is to get into a
rhythm and move in sync with
the water and your boat.
It can haveit a calming
meditative feel while still
giving you a serious workout.
All right.
How cool is this?
Whoo!
Look how big that tree is.
it's like nice and peaceful out
here.
>> I'm the.. Only one that means
I think people really need to
come out here actually really
calm out here.
As you navigate the lake,
you'll pass by strawberry hill,
an island in the middle of the
lake with a waterfall trails
and tons of wildlife like
ducks, turtles and birds.
>> strawberry hill is connected
by two bridges to the park
and it's the highest point
in golden gate park.
It includes huntington falls, a
110 foot tall artificial
waterfall that feeds into the
lake.
There's also the chinese
pavilion a gift from san
francisco's sister city.
Taipei, taiwan.
Isit's a charming place to rest
and take in the views.
Ooh, that was a workout for the
arms.
I love boating.
That's a lot of funun getting out
on the lake.
But now I got too look at the
legs.
Let's go
skate.
We're here at this game place
on sixth and fulton.
Beautiful day.
I thinkga I'm going to rent some
rollerblades.
>> let's get rolling s
.
Good job.
>> skates on skates.
If you're looking for aka fun way
to spend a sunday afternoon,
check out the skating place.
It's near sixth avenue
in kennedy drive and has a
great surface that's perfect
for practicing or hanging out
with fellow skaters.
Ohgi, man.
This is, uh.
This is very nostalgic for the
millennial and me 90s.
Playing with my boys someoc
street hockey.
I haven't ridden blades in a
whiles but it's hitting me like
riding a g bike.
>> right.
Let's go.
Here.
>> I'm here at the free sundae
roller disco party from noonn to
5 P.M..
>> the godfather escape brings
his mobile
deejay unit
and plays groovy tunes for you
to skate here.
And if you need skates no
worries.
Rentals are available nearby
fromal 11 A.M. To 6 P.M. On the
weekends starting at just $12
an hour for kids and 20 for
everyone else right.
The skating place has been here
since 1986 and it got are fresh
makeover in 2022 with new
pavement and a stunning mural
by local artist amy steadman.
>> the mural called psychedelic
golden gate skate features a
colorful design that celebrates
the park's roller skatingteig
history.
>> plus it was created
in collaboration with the
church of eight wheels, which
is all about keeping the
skating spirit alivesp.
>> this is fun.
I had no idea this was over
here.
San francisco has everything.
Oh, it's on the side of getting
back on some roller blades.
>> it's like being a little
kid.
This is go and get adventures.
And I'm michael baltazar from
S.F. Tv.
Thanks for watching and you
will do is just bring up a
question that's not being here
you get dizzy.
>> oh, dizzy.
For me itte was I we had
neighbors growing up that were
told my dad like he's raising
me wrong for having me pursue
these things that aren't
traditionally female roles.
>> I think the biggest barrier
just to anyone in general is
when you have I cultural norms
that make you feel like you
can't do something that make
you doubt yourself, that make
you feel like you shouldn't be
there.
Iee don't belong I mean those are
those to me are the biggest
barriers.
>> and so I thinkef that's the
thing to focus on the most is
belonging.
Everyone should belong here.
>> we women's division we train
women, girls, gender expansive
folks and music production
and the recording arts.
And so we have everything from
girls in the maker classes fors
middle and high school girls
and genderse expansive you.
And then we have certification
or where I'm academy
certification program so that
would be for women and gender
expansive adults entering this
industry then they progress
into the internship program.
So we have a paid internship
program where they're working
in these studios but also
helping to mentor the youth
in our youth programs.
And then there's the job
placementeam component of that.
Most of the time we're hiring
interns as are instructors
in our programs and then as
engineers in our studios here
we also have conferences we do
all over the country and we
also have concerts called local
sirens that we feature bay area
women and gender expansive
artists the philippines w is what
is very ironic that we've got
to have she's finger that I
heard ours was someone else's
point of view wam is an
education forward organization
and so it's anan advocacy
organization dedicated to
closing the gender gap that's
pretty egregious and the audio
and production industry is so I
started out of the need to
answer that question why is
there such a critical gender
gap in this industry?
So it started at city college a
small group of women students
in my program.
Why are there so few of us
in this class?
And I was honestly ashamed that
I didn't have the answer being
such a feminist myself I was
like wow, I never I never
thought of this.
I've been in this industry for
decades and why have I accepted
it of all people?
>> right?
So it was mostly out of that
and then it was just unraveling
it for me.
>> so I actually started with
the internship last fall
and just fell in love with all
of the things about women's
audio mission just because it's
so diverse there's just so many
different aspects of audio that
I did not know about and I feel
like my whole eyes opened up
and also I just gained a lot of
confidence in myself and other
fans and people in the
industry.
I felt like there was more
solidarity, a connection
and community.
>> ironically my time in the
industry has all been pretty
good so I think what happened
is I was raised by a father who
is an engineer so I was a
comfortable being surrounded by
men all the time in his lab I
was very accustomed to
technology so when I got into
industry all of my mentors were
men but I also at n the same time
saw I had a a very unique
experience that got me
into
that place where I could be
fluent in that and navigate
nf
something that was difficult
and it was the norm for me.
What if itndle wasn't?Al
essentially women was created
to provide that fork everybody
like you have this environment,
you're surrounded by
technology, you're surroundedd d I
by people that are going to
support you and get you into
this industryy
in a good way.
>> is
it too high?
Oh no.
I've always been interested
in audio.
I never was trained in musicst,
took piano lessons when I was a
kid.
I never really pursued it when
I grew up because you know
there's not a lot of women
around me who were doing that
and my family's not really
musically inclined family.
So when I went to davis I think
the first time that I tookt a
music class I was one of the
only few females in the class
so I used to like it was like a
roadie for my dad.
I would like load up the mixer
,the monitors and the giant
speakers two gigs and I would
helpd like run out the actual
cables and take things down
setting up mikes.
>> I used to do a all of that
growing up and it never even
occurred to me that that was a
field t that I could at all
and then one that I could
pursue because I didn't nobody
else was doing it.
It was like n my dad and then I
would go with him to studios
sometimes and see all of the
men and that studio I've been
doing for n five years now
there's a lot of comments you
get just like oh wow like
you're a girl deejay like
that's crazy.
Like that's so wild.
And I definitely had like great
moments where it doesn't happen
like I had coworkers who are
males and they treat me like
super equal telling me what to
do but they don't correct me
in ways that make me feel like
less.
I've definitely experienced the
opposite but I do always notice
when I get mistreated just
hands on like you don't know
what you're doing ratherr than
just asking me what I'm doing,
the amount of consistent times
that it happens. Is like
and then when I talk to other
females they like say the same
things and like it's just kind
of like funny because I, I know
that most men don't experience
it and I think that's like the
main thing that triggers me
like when I experience
different treatment and I think
that happens a lot e e and the
audio world we didn't initiate
from undergrad or anything I
think the industry is changing.
>> I think it's changing
slowly.
There's still that issue are we
making these places that are
places of belonging for
everybody?
>> I don't think so.
>> having ao studio where it's
not all run by cis white men
which is like most studios
these studios are the only ones
in the world built and run
entirely byud women and gender
diverse folks.
>> it's still not likeun super
normalized that there's
opportunities for girls
and womenth, non-binary people.
>> we gope into schools and so so
middle schoolers and high
schoolers know that this is a
fieldlea that this is a thing.
They're many different jobs you
can have in this field from
producing podcasts to like
setting up live shows.
>> s there's so many things you
can do when you get to go
in there and teach them all
these audio skills and actually
give them equipment like ipads
and then teach them how to makem
music and then they actually
get to come in here and record
stuff giving the tools tols
people who don't have it that's
like really important to me.
So that's kind
of why I was
like wow.
Like I want to be there for
other fans and people who
don't have the opportunity
and like also just to be like a
mentor for them to really push
them to just like experiment
mess up and like you're not
going to break it t or like it
doesn't matter if it sounds bad
like that's kind of like the
point is
just to like try it.
So I think like my ultimate
goal is for them to just be
confident in what they're doing
and passionate and wanting to
ask for help and just really
excited about learningci
and excited about making music
and expressing themselves.
It really changedak my life to
just realize that I'm actually
like really talented in this
field
I can make music without
being classically trained.
It's reallyly amazing to be able
to be part of that process
and ushering women into the
field.
We can entirely transform how
the technology a part of what
you hear every day we can put
somebody and have women's
perspectives and points of view
in that every time it affects
the story that affects h the
messaging.
I think our best example is how
we've transformed an entire
city.
I mean it's really to a place
where the pretty major artist
that was on tour one of the men
in the band was like I don't
get it.
There's women everywhere I I go
and and then the person was
like but you're in san
francisco you're just like oh
you're right, it's here.
Most venues now have our
graduates.
>> we're very grateful to the
city of san francisco foror that u
reason because they supported
us at the very beginning when
my mom made up my mind to
follow your curiosity
and interest and don't let
anybody get in the way of that
whateverin is presented to you go
for it no matter what I look
like we're here for a reason.
Find what it is you deserve to
find with live and somebody
else.
Tell you what it is.
Whtyou're the only one that can
know what you're supposed to doow
and go do it.
>>dodo yeah and also go to the san
francisco government.
>> I be glad to say hello
and welcome everyone as we
celebrate arab american
heritage month here in san
francisco at city hall.
Yes.
Where we can apply and I just
want to introduce myself my
name is angelina.
I am with the mayor's office of
community affairs and I am one
of the liaisons who are helping
work with the arab-american
community.
So any issues you ever have
please come find me.
I try and be everywhere all at
once as much as possible.
And with that I want to hand it
over to the mayor.
Hi everybody.
Thank you for coming out.
It's good to see everybody.
I want to thank all of the
community members who are here
today.
i want to thank supervisor
mahmoud's office for helping to
organize this event as we
commemorate commemorate arab
heritage month.
Um, before we get started I
want to acknowledge an incident
that happened right here at
city hall last week.
Um I want to be clear with
everybody that hate speech
and hate crimes anywhere have
no place in san francisco.
Um, and so I wanted to start by
saying that they agree uh, my
team and I are working
diligently to make sure san
francisco is safe for everyone
and that no one experiences
hate based on their identity as
a city we must do better during
arab heritage month I've been
grateful to experience the rich
culture, history
and contributions of arab
americans to this great city we
celebrate on the streets of the
tenderloin with san francisco's
first ever e street festival
which was great and you did a
great job supervisor we also
recently broke fast together
here at city hall sharing a
meal and a moment with
community and it's it's
inspiring to see not just our
elected leaders here today but
our fearless community
organizers and advocates the
people who do so much for san
francisco each and every day as
we mark arab american heritage
month here in san francisco
and across the nation I hope
this month serves as a reminder
of the contributions the arab
community has made
and continues to make to our
city and to our country from
arts and culture to small
businesses, civic leadership
and community building
arab-americans have
strengthened the fabric of san
francisco in every corner of
the city.
I look forward to continuing to
celebrate to stand alongside
our arab and muslim communities
.
And with that I would like to
present this proclamation
declaring APRIL 2025 arab
american heritage month.
>> thank you.
You right doing some other
things like I think.
All right.
And I would like to call up
and before I call you up
supervisor mahmood, I want to
also say welcome to supervisor
cheyenne champ.
>> thank you for being here.
Aleikum, everyone I wanted to
acknowledge as we are an
arab-american heritage month
this is a month where a lot of
things are going on globally
nationally and locally here
in san francisco when we
recognize arab-american
heritage month at the board of
supervisors last week I think
one of the first times in many
time thanks to us
and supervisor dorsey's office
who wrote the resolution
declaring it for the first
time.
>> let's give her a round of
applause as well I think
and tell me she was the only
muslim on the second floor so
um but about arab-american
heritage month it's a
recognition I think of both our
commitment as a city to ensure
safety but also joy for the
community on the issue of
safety, we have heard loud
and clear from many people who
are here gathered of the drug
crisis of the homelessness
crisis that is in the
tenderloin where so many of our
arab families live.
I know we have a lot of
representatives here from 2a1
turk here today sahar rothwell
from the tenderloin community
school and we've heard from
them so many times not just
those issues but also about
harassment and racist attacks
and we heard that for several
years and I know over the last
year has been the highest
documented increase over the
last six months, I believe of
continued attacks against
arab-americans and the
mayor alluded to it as well
just last week when we were
actually introducing and voting
on the arab-american heritage
month, one of the members of
the audience who came and spoke
was a victim to that same type
of attack who was told to go
back to her own country who
here has been told before to go
back to their own country,
raise their hand.
It's something that we're all
too familiar with
and unfortunately should not
continue.
Similarly, I want to
acknowledge that the national
level we have seen an
administration that is
weaponising arab identity to
target political enemies
and we're here today to say as
well that this has no place
even organizations here in this
room have been targeted online
and told to be arrested.
That's not what we stand for
in san francisco and that's not
type of language and or the
language of the democratic
party.
And as a democratic party
member and as a board of
supervisors member, we are here
to stand with those
organizations to say that does
not stand in san francisco as
well.
But amidst that doom and gloom
like the mayor alluded to, we
have a lot of joy and we're
seeing things bounce back for
the first time in years, drug
dealing arrests are down in the
tenderloin for the first time
in years we've had a street
fair that was determined by the
community, by organizers here,
by them to bring joy to our
neighborhood and that is done
because of our new mayor,
because of the new board of
supervisors working together to
prioritize these issues.
And I want to again acknowledge
this administration and our
board of supervisors and the
community here for making that
possible for having your voices
heard.
So thank you again to the
community that made that
possible.
And lastly to end on that note
of joy, I want to bring up
laura from redding who asks to
sing for all of us as we end on
that note of what the future of
this city represents.
So I think I want to get your
stool back.
So one side.
Hi, my name is laura.
I mean everybody's out of cool
.
And my question is jordan and I
want to sing your song about
the body part.
So make sure you can see her
beautiful face like oh I can
you can you know we got you.
There you go.
>> there you go.
Oh, lady.
Watch on feeling and we'll be
the wash flat tide li watch
what feeling and what bfe wash
off that pad make up that lead
cover man look at that little
andy done that.
Dun dun dun dun dun dun dun.
Next I would like to introduce
a trustee trustee to give some
remarks.
All right.
Good afternoon.
That was amazing.
Can we give another round of
applause for laura?
That's a hard act to follow.
Thank you so much for all of
you for being here today.
I want to thank you supervisor
mahmood and mayor lurie for
putting this amazing event on
and I want to also give a big
shout out to angelina.
So thank you, mayor lurie for
hiring angelina, an
arab-american on his team
and staff.
My name is alia chisti.
I'm a trustee at city college
of san francisco.
And it is incredible to stand
before you today after years of
tireless advocacy by arab
american leaders to have this
month recognized, we finally
have it here.
So thank you former PRESIDENT
Biden thank you for holding
this event.
And so but at the same time we
now have someone in the white
house who once again views
arab-americans through a lens
of fear and suspicion.
>> a reminder of how much of
the work remains arab-americans
are racially diverse,
religiously diverse
and culturally rich, yet too
often they are misunderstood
stereotype and villainized.
This month is not just a
celebration.
It's an opportunity to
challenge those harmful
narratives.
Arab-americans are a vital part
of this nation's social fabric
and absolutely a vital part of
san francisco.
They've opened businesses led
movements, raised families
and built communities that
welcome everyone.
And on a side note, if you have
not tried yemeni coffee or been
to older less jerusalem, you
have not lived life so strongly
recommend checking out city
college of san francisco is
proud to have produced leaders
like ahmed al ahmed al-khateeb,
a palestinian american
activist.
And through programs like
critical middle east, southwest
and north african studies,
north africa studies city
college is committed to lifting
up these histories cultures
and voices that are too often
marginalized.
And now it is my great pleasure
to introduce someone who is a
force to be reckoned with laura
laura castellani who is the
executive director of iraq.
>> so please join me in giving
her a very warm welcome.
>> good afternoon.
My name is laura saleem yusef
is limon moussa aka swanee
and I am a proud daughter of
palestinian refugees.
I start by saying that because
it's important to name as we
celebrate arab american
heritage month we are
celebrating the totality of our
identities, our cultures, our
traditions and our histories.
>> as the executive director of
iraq, I am proud to stand here
today to celebrate our county's
leadership in recognizing
arab-american heritage month.
And I want to appreciate
mayor daniel lurie
and supervisor mahmood.
And also mahnaz and her office
and supervisor chen for really
demonstrating what it looks
like to offer courageous,
principled leadership in these
times of precariousness
and danger and fear.
This month is a celebration of
our resilience and a reminder
that standing with the arab
and southwest asian north
african communities is
essential in the fight against
bigotry and repression across
the entire united states.
>> arab-americans have
contributed to this country for
nearly 150 years and yet our
history is often too often
erased by racism and xenophobia
narratives now fueled by the
federal administration.
Today arab communities across
the bay area are facing rise
in repression, discrimination,
hate violence both for who they
are, who we are as people
and for speaking out for peace
and justice.
Over the past year and a half
we have endured immense trauma
watching our ongoing genocide
in gaza while facing growing
attacks right here at home.
through our arab youth program
and through our legal
immigration services, we are
hearing stories each day of
young people who are terrified
who are being discriminated
against and even targeted by
ice simply for speaking out for
human rights.
>> in this climate this
celebration matters.
It sends a powerful message
that our communities are not
only seen, our communities are
not only valued but our
communities are also defended.
We thank you for standing with
us and we look forward to
building a future where all
people in this city can live
in dignity with justice
and liberation for all.
>> thank you.
>> I have the pleasure of
introducing a tenderloin
community leader right now
hussein gradwell will be
speaking representing the
tenderloin community school
and the work of the city
in this city.
>> so thank you for joining us
.
Alaikum and marhaba, everyone.
Peace be upon you all and hello
.
My name is radwan hussein and I
work at the underlying
community school as an arabic
speaking family.
Well.
I want to start today by
thanking mayor laurie
and supervisor bilal mahmud for
giving arab americans this
space and space to be seen here
and and truly celebrated today
isn't just a celebration.
It's a tribute to resilience,
to the hopes that cross the
ocean and deserts to the dreams
that live on no matter what.
For generations the arab
community has been part of
and has been part of the heart
of this city working, serving,
building and loving sometimes
quietly but always with deep
right across every field
in education, health care,
business, public service
and arts.
Arab has given their best to
this city with love, dedication
and excellence.
And across the country arab
americans have helped shape
history.
Leaders like ralph nader who
fought for consumer rights,
helen thomas who broke barriers
in journalism.
DR. Michael debakey who
reshaped the heart surgery
and rami malik who showed the
world the power of our stories
through films.
And now they follow the young
yemeni immigrant who marched
with cesar chavez and gave his
life fighting for justice.
And when we given the chance,
arab americans lead with
brilliance like mary alexander
buster, the first egyptian born
woman to become a mayor in the
united states.
We also honor those who built
our community right here at
home.
Nabila mangal, a palestinian
activist therapist and the
light in our community who
healed and uplifted so many.
If DECEMBER I was just third
nurse at the general hospital
who was our fearless advocate
for decades and was the only
arabic speaking person during
covid a debate and the journey
from california's first
certified arabic translated at
san francisco's supreme court.
We come from 22 countries each
with our own stories
and struggles but we all are
united by one heart.
A heart had been tested by war
by exile, by loss but has never
been broken.
Many of us carry stories of
pain but we also carry stories
of strength and strains of
family and of dreams.
We still here we are proud
and we are only getting
stronger as we honor our past.
We must also invest in our
future, our youth and children.
When we open our doors to for
them and give them real chances
to lead we ensure that our
stories doesn't just continue
its source.
These include our arabic
students in schools.
They need to feel included,
valued and their culture is
honored.
Just as we celebrate
and recognize all our beloved
community heritage months we
must ensure arab american
culture and history are also
woven into the fabric of our
education.
Every young american deserves
to see themselves reflected,
respected and the proud of who
they are to every arab mother
raising the next generation
and to every young dreamer
choosing their future to every
family who came here seeking
for a new beginning.
This moment is for us this city
is our home too.
And together we will keep
building it with love, with
bright and with unstoppable
hope.
And as we speaking for our
future I am proud to introduce
an america an arab-american
youth leader and also district
five youth commissioner izzat
al emery, a voice for our.
>> good evening, everybody.
Thank you for having me here
today.
I am truly honored and thankful
to be speaking here today of
growing up I didn't see a lot
of arab or muslim leaders to
look up to in my classrooms or
to see as a role model.
This absence left the silence
one that made many of us feel
unseen.
That's why celebrating
arab-american heritage month is
so important.
It is about making future
generations to being proud of
where they come from, knowing
their roots and a source of
strength, leadership
and inspiration.
This month not only is a time
to honor arab american
contributions to our country
but it is a time to speak up at
a time at a time of injustices
and sufferings to many of our
brothers and sisters in the
middle east.
When we celebrate arab-american
heritage month, we are not just
recognizing the past.
We are shaping the future a
future where every child knows
they are seen, heard
and valued.
Thank you.
Thank you so much for having me
speak here today.
And now I'd like to introduce a
fellow yemeni city worker aseel
to give his speech.
>> thank you so much.
how are we doing today?
Good girl.
Peace and blessings be upon you
all.
First I just want to thank our
honorable mayor for letting us
and angelina for letting us be
here at this beautiful balcony
supervisor bilal mahmood for
being a champion and for us
and introducing a resolution
declaring this month as arab
heritage month.
My name is aseel farah and I'm
a proud yemeni-american.
I'm also a member of san
francisco's immigrant rights
commission and I stand before
you all today because of a
sacrifice that my father made.
My father brought me and my
family into the united states
and hope for a better life
and a better opportunities
after we fled yemen.
You know, when we came into the
great city of san francisco,
went into the tenderloin lured
by the city's possible cheapest
rent and if he had not made
that choice I might have found
myself in the chaos and the
calamities that my brothers
and sisters in yemen suffer
today in the chaos of war
and humanitarian crisis.
So with that being said, I just
want us to think about the
luxuries that are in front of
us each and every single day
that we often overlook.
I want to talk about a little
bit why arab-american heritage
month matters now more than
ever.
I think it's a time for
arab-americans to reclaim our
story.
For far too long there have
been narratives that have been
stereotypical and have been
harmful towards the community
when in light we have made
profound contributions to our
our nation and to our society.
People like juarez me who gave
us algebra laying the
groundwork of modern
mathematics and science even a
ceo whose medical texts are
pillars to medical advancements
till this day.
And with all of that said we
are still unaccounted for when
it comes to data or being
represented.
So I just want to take this
opportunity to say that there
is a middle eastern north
african act at the state
assembly and I want to thank
the city state legislature
and the state legislation
committee for basically
approving that the city support
this bill.
This will make sure that we're
represented and I'll pass it to
angelina.
>> I'm just here to close this
out.
So thank you everyone again for
making time and coming out
and celebrating this important
month with us.
To echo what everyone says
right, oftentimes we are
invisible but we are the
backbone of san francisco.
We run all the corner stores
that you go get your late night
snacks.
We run all the amazing
restaurants that you go get
your hummus and your falafel at
.
I grew up with arab-american
parents and I am very proud to
be here celebrating with you.
I also want to give a shout out
to ted market wherever you are
in the back.
They brought some delicious
food for us to enjoy.
So thank you everyone again.
Thanks.
>> do you want to keep this
and some good tv?
San francisco television loves
nobody doesn't make it a story
not say that I cannot have an
impact on and secondly that
motive and organization in this
community really I can speak
for them and tell as a
collaborator for passover I was
responsible asparaginase was an
orientation for you.
What are you somebody up into
the as of curve tv?
Yes.
Was some of san francisco this
information producer company
that in this segment of the
remote over in san francisco
and we're in forum of what are
the immigrants of san francisco
we're not coalition
interinstitutional on alcatraz
I have pineapple you are those
immigrants illustrates you that
you condemn to the amount of
money that in the us the
rhetoric would be within office
the participation ceca yes all
those immigrants the cadaver
last you that the san francisco
pork go so what will happen if
they keep going through school
system and it was just told
them your money and we will
invest with the movement the
galaxy out of the system
and thought almost underserved
and for the immigrant this is
becoming a consistent for
immigrant this quickly adap or
defenses department those
municipalities because run on
by coordinated services by the
system we asked immigrants
in san francisco where crapper
nest office in a lock is not
our position civic hospitals
immigrants but like hansel said
and so I said MRS. Romano's
departamento de salud publica
love us that are color color
the windows hello your
community communitarian talk on
a theme the coordinator said
because but I guess like I said
local centric operations like
when we earn grants it's not
back in our web cares for punto
hey over baron verde that
immigrants and don't are back
in our web based on contact
in a torres puntos claris
alfredo and see as soon I'm not
back in our community not
lament the legality we in the
senate I'm in the committee
that I travel across courses
because at this point you list
immigrants and the importance
of status immigrant unilateral
look upon component component
soon at least the this had we
saw the court electronico on
just based on eu spain mandate
information somebody eventos a
cool source well get the point
for my second case out of L.A.
Important the me that immigrant
to san francisco if the said
component then I most who now
rely on those masses known that
almost capacitors student
fundamental I was privy to this
had to be source in san
francisco immigrants in san
francisco and those is called
care organization or group care
that I service your capacities
your and you want this where
participar your blender
massacre marcello my heart is
that in for my blog assignments
ask community that is como cell
overall aggression this to
coalition resident they exist
to entry into como say civil
and or non mobile version
numeral system and this
and this error MR. Ramos as as
set to be but I slathers
immigrants for cattle san
francisco gomez complicado
pedro canasta canasta number if
the member from another matter
guest your coordinate service
shows a million barrels a day
parental municipalities but I
stole that information the
common era is ten trabalhando
is texarkana.
Yes.
Interesting equalizer papel is
pacific all the cover hands
here to correct handshake
medicamento to an event this
deposit said we took office
in a community that is so
important as by the else that
was alone was not some sort of
saloons or commercial to a
tribal and this is important
because that most coordinators
yes that's a hands yes to us so
arsenal copy the hecho diva
bill for all and ptosis social
security numbers okay as we
said it because yes it's I
hands yes but the netherlands
services those centralized
and also look at the group
within control recognize that
is the information a the
dominant existence the
information in various idioms
or global informers going
squint de la pagina web he stay
there stay where guess who took
over merabet bertie the
immigrants when in clowning
less yet than almost a lack
capacity to commit the scylla
and event the city of massive
parking and will not could get
us if they agree that all will
circles parallel commonwealth
custodian kleptocracy it this
to the corrales else could we
normally see the san francisco
stuck on the status guess on
campus control room the much
shorter more payroll in the sum
of 100 per hour care thing
unless information is going to
stand up sexy tossers you read
in san francisco work which
other righteous person nosotros
the limitation but a companion
government then therefore
that's a mighty able to render
control which has this status
for example of those fellow
books in the S.F. Gov tv san
francisco government television
.
Hello everyone welcome to S.F.
Gov tv's meet your district
supervisor series.
My name is franco finn.
I'm a first generation san
francisco born and raised
in this great city., very active
in this community.
I've been an auctioneer for
nearly two plus decades helping
to raise lots of money for many
local
schools in the area also
nonprofits.
But I'm also very known as the
voice and hype man if you will.
In-arena host for your golden
state warriors for the last two
plus decades as well.
>> but I'mls also a proud member
of the san francisco film
commission here in san
francisco.
But today I have the pleasure
to interview our
board of
supervisors PRESIDENT From
district eight rafael
mendelson.
thank you so much for joining
us fctht. T
>> thanks for having me.
Well, district eight first off
includes castro m, glen park,
novi valley diamond heights
mission, dolores and also coal
valley.
We'll dive into your district a
little bit down the road here
but let's talk about you for
instance.
I want to know more about you.
A lot of people want to know
about your history.
Where did you grow up,ou your
family background and thenou
obviously how did you end up
in san francisco?
Yeah, well ira was born
in southern california.
I'm a california kid.
Ior grew up in laguna beach until
I was 11 years old.
I was living with my mom who
sort of was deteriorate ating
as I was growing up.
She had mental health issues.
I had a grandmother in san
francisco and so I moved up
here when I was 11 to live with
her.
She was getting on in years but
I was fortunate I was a couple
of small independent schools.
Brandeis time was brandeis hill
all day school.
Yes.
And then like boarding high
school and I sort of arranged
these sort of informalh all like
do it yourself foster care
arrangements with families at
those schools ended up living
for three years with an english
teacher at lic and her husband.
.
Wow.
And that was my growing up.
And then went away for school
and went away for school
and then, you know now you're
you know, the PRESIDENT Of the
board of supervisors which
congratulations I know is a big
role in our city but we're
going to repeal the onions
in the layers in the onion
because there's so many layers
to our supervisors and getting
to know your background is
super important.
>> but why politics?
>> why did you get your career
what what what made you kind of
decide I'm going to follow this
career in politics?
>> how long ago was that?
I've always thought government
was really important
and interesting when other
little boys were like
collecting baseball cards I was
interested in, you know, who
was going to get the democratic
nomination in 198080 four.
>> and I have these scrapbooks
and when I was growing up and I
would cut up these time
magazines and like w to like, you
know, keep track of all the
different politicians.
Yeah, it was pretty nuts.
But that was kind of my
obsession as a kid and actually
afterll that first year at lick
the summer after that first
year I spent thatha summer
interning on the board of
supervisors.
Wow.
For a supervisor at thebo time
her name was doris ward.
>> okay, so remained interested
and kept my passion for
politics through college
and went to law school and got
a master's in public policy for
most of my professional work
was representing local
governments.
I see through transactional
lawyering and giving advice to
city councils and planning
commissions and planning
directors and in my spare time
I was getting involved in san
francisco nonprofits
and serving on a couple of city
commissions and then you just
it's been that ever since that
ever since labor of love
and passion.
>> yeah it's a lot of long
nights and a lot of thoughts go
into obviously your job
and your current role at the
moment.
Yeah let's let's ask you about
the you know basically what do
you hope to bring as board
PRESIDENT?
I mean that is a huge
responsibility b.
Is this something that you've
always envisioned?
thought about before?
Like when did that actually
click and say oh my gosh, let's
let's let's go for this?
>> yeah, well I think we're
in I guess every moment is
important but we're in a pretty
challenging moment with a lot
of opportunities in san
franciscoof and in city hall we
got a new mayor.
We have five new supervisors.
I've been I'm the longest
serving member of the board of
supervisors which is a little
troubling to me as time goes by
way m too you're not the veteran.
I'm now the veteran and I think
you know am and the reason for
me to be doing this right now
is that I am a consensus
builder.
I'm someone who's kind of
in the middle of the boardnous
ideologically.
I, I think I get along well
with everyone.
>> I think people see me as a
straight shooter and I really
want to see daniel lurie be
successful as mayor.
I think we the city has
enormous challenges still.
I worked well with the prior
mayor but there's an
opportunity now because I think
particularly with this new cast
of characters people willing to
give
each other a fair break
and try to work togetherli and beog
collaborative and we need to
because we have these
challenges from inner mass
challenges budget federal
government there's a lot that
you
know we're up against but I
think the fact that we do have
this potential for
collaboration w and city hall
and an opportunity to look at
some of the challenges that
we've been struggling
with for
a long time and maybe approach
them in a different way.
This is a very pivotal momentinon
in our city and I like to say
on the rise foriv sure.
>>ou I mean, you know, pandemic
was one thing.
We've gone through a lot of the
city and now it's time to kind
of bring that backnd up, bring
that gold that we know this
gold has been here foreverl.
Right?
And so we're going to do that.
Let's talk about your your
district in particular w district
eight yeah.
What are your main priorities
in your district and what has
or
been your priority and what do
you want to do in your district
district like you know like all
districts district eight has
many different neighborhoods
and they're they're all
different and they all have
different needsfeds.
We have been quite focused
in the time that I've been n
in office on the street
conditions and behavioral
health and homelessness
challenges that we see
particularlyal in in the castro
and the part of the district.
That's right.
That's the mission d although it
impacts is no it it impacts
glen park.
I mean there's not a
neighborhood in san francisco
that is not impacted by these
challenges
but we're really
focused on trying to get help
to severely mentally ill peoplee
,people with serious substance
use disorders who areer, you
know, disintegrating in plain
sight and also causing enormousw,
challenges for small businesses
for for resident residents c.
And I think we've had some
progress actually.
I mean I do think things are
better now in that regard than
they were certainlyly during the
pandemic and you know, even
even before.
But there's stilleeem a ton of work
to do.
>> there is a lot of work to
do.
But how do you ensure the
underrepresented aerns communities
in your district are heard
and also included c in some of
the decision making process
that we have to go through?
Yeahah, I actually do.
>> sangh francisco has I think alt
culture of public participation
and a real makes a real effort
to engage people who are being
impacted by decisions toeae I
personally want to hear all
sides of an issue t hear from the
people who are actually going
to be impacted by the decisions
we're making
.
Si think that's part of our
culture as a city and it's also
part of what I thinkur is
important as an elected
official and as an elected
official you have to balanceci a
lot of things especially
in your role as board PRESIDENT
Have to do balance how do you
navigate balancing competing
interests especiallyo when it's
time to make those decisions
in the city?
>> how do you balancet'o how doou
you find that perfect?
Nothing's perfect.
>> we all know that.
Butfe one of the things I try to
do is get people to talk to
each other.
Peoplele love yelling at their
elected officials but in some
ways you'reel elected officials
are a stand in for a set ofls
people in your community who
mayet not agree with the position
that you have.
People get very frustrateday when
the city doesn't pursue
policies that seem self-evident
correct to them I think it's
useful to make people grapple
with this, you know, with the
perspectives of people who
don't see it the same way.
And in this w city.
right.
Even though you know, we're we
don't have that many you know,
conservatives say there's a lot
of room in the middle and the
left to disagree.
Yeah, and people do disagree
and I think it's good for
people to hear each other out
and actually start pressing
against the the areas where,
you know, those disagreementsal.
Right.
Maybe are keeping the city from
moving forward and so that's
kind of my style in my district
around particular issues
and it's also my style on the
board of supervisors okay if we
can get people who don't agree
necessarily or think they
disagree to sort of work out
work out details
and sometimes
we don't agree as much.
>> we don't disagree as much as
we think we do.
Yeahetwe.
>> and it's hard to have the
same opinion for everything all
the time you're going to have
differences but navigating
through that is very
challengingg and tough.
But you everybody has valid
points.
You just got to listen
to them
all right and put them all
together.
I think it's good for people to
remember that and try to t try to
live by that.
>> that's true.
On a lighter side, you know a
,
san francisco we know is a
beautiful backdrop.
So many things
to do, places to
see lots of great food.
I mean we've got it all.
>> I personally feel a lot of
us do.
What would you normally do?
I'm just curious.
I'm not like a sun let's say if
you didn't have any work to n dous
and you just have some free
time who has no free timee right
?
But what would you do?
What what's something that that
rafael would say youe know this
would be my kind of day in san
francisco.
Ideal day.
I love getting w w outside.
I love seeing my friends.
So if I doov have it is rare that
I have an unscheduled sunday
but if I do ii have an unscheduled
sunday, you know, getting out
and seeing some we we have
amazing natural areas and parks
in the city whether it's you
know, ocean beach or land's end
or the northwest waterfront or
crissy field or glen canyon
in my district or buena vista
park or you know, we just we
are so when I haven't gotten
there I've left out moste of the
parks that are amazing in the
city but there's there's so
many amazing
races to get
outdoors and walk around and I
love you know I love an urban
hike okay.
>> and urban hike is always fun
and I rediscover
my own city
doing that as well.
Walk through all these
neighborhoods and backdrops are
so beautiful.
>> you know the city has so
many gems.
I know that it's hard to pick
favorites
and whatnot but what
is the bright light that you
can b highlight that you know
since you've been in office
that you're district has
highlighted, demonstrated
and shown just a perfect
example like this is this is
what my district is like.
This is like that's a win for
district eight.
What is that moment?
>> is there one I mean there's
so many neighborhoods that are
a win for the whole city.
I you know, dolores park is
righti in the heart of love it
part of the district and it's
definitely been through some
challenges and during the
pandemic there were you know,
tents pretty much all the way
along delora street and lots of
people camping in the park
and actually some concerns
about safety shootings and you
know, not to say that those
problems are all gone because
they're not and there is
violence still and there are
still occasional horrible
events and but butcc I do think
that that area has become
safer.
More pleasant.
Yeah.
And better and it's just such a
great I mean it brings people
from all walks of life and all
partsnf of the city.
>> so dolores park's
great
doloresor park is great.
>> and you know what's lovely
about our city is probablyy
within ten minutes you can find
some park, some outdoor public
space that can be used for a
variety of things and I think
we're very lucky we could walk.
It's a true walking city.
Yeah.
And so talking about your
district we talked about a
highlight there.
What is somethinggh that you wantt
to do in this kind of short
term future but then also the
long term future of like thelo
legacy especially when it comes
to your particular district
kind of like the threetr to five
and then like that 5 to 10
and beyond start with the kind
of theth sort of immediate future
what what do you hope toed see?
I think as I look at my my
district and the neighborhood
that kind of means the most of
the world and also has the
greatest challenges is the
castrohe okay?
It means most world because
it's where youst know, lgbt
politics in a lot of ways were
born harvey multi-camera shot
yes you know lrn is there so many
of the marches that were
critical for the community for
the fight against hiv all these
I mean that you know, it's ano
neighborhood with incredible
history.
It does and it is also of the
neighborhoods in my district,
the one that's been most
impacted by degraded street
conditions
where there are the
highest level of vacancies,
where small businesses
and residents are really
struggling with our inability
to deal effectively with mental
health challenges we have.
>> and so for me with these
last two years that I have
in office, I really want w to
make some progress on having
places that are appropriate for
people with severe mental
illness.
I've worked on expanding our
our inventory of beds for
people with behavioral health
issues in the time that I've
been on the board and I'm proud
of the work that we've done but
we still have an acute shortage
of the kindhe of beds you would
use for someone who needs to be
conserved and that's a facility
that has a lock on the front
door.
You don't get to leave unless
you know people decide that you
know you can go out and you
know you're losing a level of
autonomy but you're also
getting the care that you need.
Yeah, I as I as you goti out
in san francisco are probably
much more in neighborhoods that
I don't represent.
But even in some of the
neighborhoods I do represent
you see folks who who need that
that level of careep s we have 140
of those beds.
We've applications to the state
for funding for 100 more of
those budgets increase that
and I want to work on trying m to
make that happen over these
last try to double basically
coming closela to doubling it.
Yeah I co-chaired a task force
on this problem over the you
know the through the last year
of the administration we put
outas a report the day before her
last day in office but
basically it was talking about
the need for this kind of bed
and also for more boarding care
facilities for people who maybe
don't need to be in a locked
facility
but do need something
that has a higher level of care
than you're going to get say
turn into a permanent
supportive housing unit as
though this is not you know, we
don't I don't think we need
these types of beds for most
unhoused people I don't think
we need them to deal with our
encampment most of our
encampment challenges.
But there's a set of folks who
really do need that higher
level of care.
The state of california went
out of the business in the 20th
century.
No one's really gotten, you
know, stepped upe 2 and we can't
do it all in san francisco but
we can do more than what we're
doing and wee should.
Okay.
Well thanks for sharing that
and I want to highlight a
littlele something different on
the castro is one of my
favorite districts and areas
in san francisco.
>> I live literally minutes
away.
I'm a big movie and film buff.
Yeah, milk is one of my most
favorite favorite movies of all
timene about san francisco based
about san francisco right.
I would love you know I have to
throw in a film commission.
Yes.
Questionou in there I mean we
have some iconic places to
shoot from in the city.
Castro has got a lot of
history.
I want to get another movie
what would be another l movie
coming out of the castro be
like like because there's so
much history
the castro
theater.
What about that?
Yeah.
Is there any you know what an
iconic
place.
Yeah, well the castro theater
is a great place to open movies
and you know.
Yeah.
And they have had great
openings there and how fun it
was to have milk, get shots
obviously.
Yeah.
That the movie gets shot in in
the castro yeah I mean thank
you for your work on the film
commission to try and get more
films made and some more san
francisco is good marketing for
us and people remember those
movies that was shot here that
that that you know pursuit of
happiness all those but yeah
well I'm hoping the cast
theater will bee open soon.
Oh I can't wait like all
projects that's going more
slowly than we would we would
like but yeah have you seen the
inside did you get bored?
>> actually I'll tell you
something I actually painted a
little slab of paint at the
top.
I did a little behind the
scenes feature.
>> yeah.
When it was gutted out.
Yeah.
Have t you been at the top?
That thing has not been touched
for nearlyto
100 plus years
and they were refurbish into
looks beauty with this amazing
detail unbelievable when they
you know it was timothy
pflueger I think but you know
the detail they put into that
building every little detail
most people are never going to
see it.
Those of us who were lucky
enough to likee get the hard
hats which is pretty high I'm
not good with heights.
>> yeahd, but did you get a
chance to like I didn't get to
paint.
I don't know whyt I still got a
little piece of history.
>> one little thing and I asked
for information.
Is it okay because this is a
historicsk building.
Okay, but no one's been up
there for so long.
But what aorok bright gem like
that's just a just a great
yeah, you know I'm into film
and all that.
>> it's important that I keep
showing film.
It is?
Yeah.
And thenen that's it's a
beautiful part of our city.
>> it's great.
Well let's talk about I'm t going
to close out with this.
Thank you for sharing.
There's so much to talk about
but such
little time but I do
have these rapid fire questions
just get to know youtt a little
bit.
>> oh my gosh.
One word answers now some of
the other supervisors they were
kind of going on I want to hear
just fast paced.
What comes to mind when I throw
in some questions there either
this or that.
>> you ready?
I'm concernedhr.
>> okay.
All right.
I'll make it easy for you.
How about this?
Let's startig with the easy first
one about this giants or
dodgers f?
Giants you said so.
Yeah.
Oh, hear crowd's in the back
over there.
>> they're going to answer
giants the kids are excited.
>> yeah.
I always ask and give you know
so calm folks I said okay you
know you have your so called
rivalries but your norcal
services go all the way.
>> yeah good answer.
I love it.
Okay.
Hiking or biking a?
>> hiking.
Okay.
Cable car.
Bus.
Cable carkiik.
>> okay.
Best view in the city.
That's twin peaks of twin peaks
.
>> I do love twin peaks.
Okay.
Can you tell me public park or
a private garden?
>> public park?
Of course.
How about this golden gate
bridge or bay bridge?
Golden gate bridge for sure.
Coffee or tea?
Coffee.
Okay.
Cats or dogs?
Dogs.
Middle
window or aisle seat
and flying aisle.
>> okay.
>> I'm an aisle guy.
Yes.
That means easy exits,
bathrooms.
We just I don't want to be, you
know, in over people.
Well for some reasons find it
be you
have to crawl over mens
but I don't want to like that's
an important question
especially when you're
traveling with otheravr
people.
What don you want?
Right.
Okay.
Just a handful more sunset or o>>
sunrise sunrise bart or
muni
muni oc tech or the arts the
sorry tech but the arts the
arts.
>> okay, well I'm with you on
that couple more foggy mornings
in san francisco or would you
want those clear skies the very
few that we do least but what
do you it took me till I was
like 16 years old to realize
the whole city was not living
in fog all the time.
But but I ifo think I like I don't
live I grew up in the fog
and all of the fog.
>> soo so the the clear skies.
The clear skies.
Carl the fog if you're
listening carl raphael said
he's going to go clear skies.
Okay, one last thing if you had
to pick between four flavors
I'm going to give youou chocolate
vanilla strawberryla or greenea
tea.
>> chocolate chocolate.
>> well, I got a little
something here to close out our
interview.
what surprises?
>> surprises?
You've heard of the yeah.
Golden gate fortune cookie?
Cutter.
Amazing.
You said chocolate.
So pick one.
Okay, soo
ouou that one.
>> allll right, now read the
fortune and let's see if you
can answer this question.
>> see how can can read it out
loud and then tell us kind of
how it relates to who you are t
and maybe what you're doing.
Obviously your current role
what is it you are acutely
sensitive to your environment,
cutely sensitive to your
environment. Y.
Okay.
How would you apply that as weho
close out this interview
segment?
>> well, as you we do a lot of
environmental work in my office
so I'm going to choose I'm
going to choose to read it as
you know, that's good.
>> t we're trying to do work for
the environment.
That's very good answer.
Well, thank you for making our
area district yeah so nice
and it was really great to talk
to you guys.
>> this is amazing.
I want to eat that cookie now
you could eat it because I'm
eating the cookie either cookie
there you go.
>> cookie it's all good.
Well, thank you so much.
District board of supervisors
PRESIDENT Rafael edelman, thank
you so much for joining us.
If you want to find out more
about ourng city, we have a great
programing also if you want to
see your meetings live.
You can also tune in on S.F.
Gov tv dot org.
See you next time
.
>>
S.F. Gov tv san francisco
government television
.
All right.
Ready?
Yeah.
In your notes that you know
action was taken in new
typically times.
You can disclose.
Okay.
>> all right.
Are we ready?
>> yes.
Okay.
All right, folks, we are back
into open session.
No action was taken in closed
session.
MAY I have a motion that the
board finds that it is in the
best interest the public that
the board elect not to disclose
its closed session
deliberations.
>> so moves moved by chan
seconded by cheryl.
>> MADAM Clerk, will you please
call the roll?
MR. PRESIDENT, you can do that
without objection.
>> we will do that without
objection.
The motion passes.
And then I guess we there's no
other names on the roster.
So this closed session has been
held and is now filed.
>> okay.
MADAME Clerk, do we have any
imperative agenda items?
>> I have none to report.
mr. PRESIDENT, can you read the
in memoriam today?
>> today's meeting will be
adjourned in memory of the
following beloved individuals.
On behalf of supervisor
and guardian for the late
lieutenant colonel robert l
powell and on behalf of
supervisor chen for the late
MISS Antoinette jamil.
Thank you, MADAM Clerk.
I think that brings us to the
end of our agenda.
>> do we have any further
business before us today?
I have nothing.
There's no further business.
>> thank you.
We are adjourned.